[MUSIC PLAYING]
[音乐播放]
SPEAKER 1: Hello.
演讲者1：你好
Welcome to lecture three of GD50.
欢迎来到GD50的第三讲
Today, we're going be talking about Match 3, as shown by the little cubes
今天 我们将讨论第三场比赛 如小方块所示
here on the slide.
就在滑梯上
Match 3 originated a little earlier than 2001,
第三场比赛比2001年稍早一些
but the first big game that came out that was
但出现的第一场重要比赛是
a sort of genre staple of Match 3 was Bejeweled, shown here on the screen.
屏幕上显示的是《第三场比赛》的一种风格
This is a more modern incarnation of Bejeweled,
这是一个更现代的宝石化身
but it came out originally in 2001.
但它最初是在2001年出版的
It was actually a web browser game, and the formula is very simple.
这实际上是一款网络浏览器游戏 公式非常简单
The premise is you have a grid of different colored or shaped items,
前提是你有一个由不同颜色或形状的物品组成的网格
usually pretty small, like eight by eight, or so.
通常很小 像八乘八 或者更小
And your goal is just to simply, like the name says, match three or more
你的目标就是 正如名字所说 简单地匹配三个或更多
of them in a row.
他们排成一排
If you do, you get a certain number of points.
如果你这样做了 你会得到一定数量的积分
Matching usually more than three gives you more points, or a bonus.
匹配三个以上通常会给你更多的分数 或者是额外的奖励
And whenever you match three, the blocks will disappear from the grid,
当你匹配三个时 这些块就会从网格中消失
and they'll be replaced by more blocks.
它们将被更多的街区取代
And the ones that you made holes for, the blocks above them
还有你挖洞的那些 它们上面的积木
will come down via gravity.
会通过重力坠落
This is a more modern incarnation of the formula.
这是这一公式更现代的化身
This is Candy Crush, which I think most people know.
这是糖果粉碎传奇 我想大多数人都知道
It was a very big hit on mobile devices, and otherwise around 2013, 2012,
它在移动设备上大受欢迎 在2013、2012年左右
and that's probably the most recent big Match 3 style game that's come out,
这可能是最新推出的大型比赛3风格的游戏
but there are a lot of other takes on it--
但也有很多其他的观点--
different versions that try to add new features, and stuff.
不同的版本 试图添加新的功能和东西
This is the game that we'll be putting together today, and I'll show you how,
这是我们今天要做的游戏 我将向你们展示如何
and we'll be covering a few other things as well.
我们还将介绍一些其他方面的内容
So the topics today, we'll be covering, first
所以今天的话题 我们首先要讲的是
of all, a fundamental concept in dynamic languages, a lot of dynamic languages,
最重要的是 动态语言的一个基本概念 许多动态语言
and also Lua.
还有卢亚
It's called anonymous functions, which are functions
它被称为匿名函数 它们是函数
that are first class, meaning that they operate as data types,
是第一类的 这意味着它们作为数据类型运行
and so we can do some fancy stuff with those.
所以我们可以用这些东西做一些奇特的事情
Tweening, which means just taking one thing,
补丁 这意味着只拿一样东西
and interpolating its value between two values from 1,
并将其值内插在从1开始的两个值之间
to a destination value over time, which is a very important thing in games.
随着时间的推移目标价值 这在游戏中是非常重要的事情
You can do things like move objects.
你可以做一些事情 比如移动物体
We can also tween their opacity.
我们还可以对它们的不透明度进行补间
Just sort of asynchronous behavior, and asynchronous variable manipulation.
只是一种异步行为 以及异步变量操作
Timers, very important.
定时器 非常重要
We can time something to happen at certain intervals,
我们可以按一定的时间间隔对某事进行计时
or after a certain length of time has passed
或者在一段时间过去之后
to get us past the idea of storing different timed variables,
为了让我们克服存储不同时间变量的想法
or different counters, and break away, and keep timer objects that
或不同的计数器 并分开 并保留
will take care of this for us.
会帮我们处理这件事的
We'll see how we do that with a specific library.
我们将看看如何使用特定的库来做到这一点
And then we'll get to the actual details of Match 3, and how to solve matches,
然后我们将了解比赛3的实际细节 以及如何解决比赛
and how to account for that.
以及如何解释这一点
Fill in the grid, account for when we actually solve a match,
填入网格 说明我们实际解决匹配的时间
and repopulate it once we've done so.
一旦我们这样做了 就重新填充它
We'll talk about how to do this procedurally.
我们将讨论如何在程序上做到这一点
It's very simple compared to, I think, Breakout's more procedural layout
我认为 与Breakout更程序化的布局相比 这非常简单
system, but it's still randomisation, and we'll talk about that.
系统 但它仍然是随机性的 我们将讨论这一点
And then last, if we have time, we'll talk about sprite art,
最后 如果我们有时间 我们将谈论精灵艺术
and palettes, which is a big fundamental thing when you're doing 2D game
和调色板 这是你在做2D游戏时最基本的东西
development, and something that this, and Breakout's sprite sheet
发展 以及这个和Breakout的精灵单子
took advantage of was the idea of using, on purpose, a restricted set of colors,
利用的是故意使用有限的一组颜色的想法
a palette for creating your 2D art, and there
一个用于创建2D艺术的调色板 还有
are a lot of really cool, and impressive things we can do with that.
有很多非常酷的 令人印象深刻的事情 我们可以用它来做
But first, I'd like to actually show what we'll be running today in class.
但首先 我想展示一下我们今天在课堂上要讲的内容
So I'm going to come here into my directory.
因此 我将进入我的目录
Make sure I'm in the right place, which I am.
确保我在正确的地方 我确实是
So this is part of the distribution code, which is online.
这是分发代码的一部分 它是在线的
So there's a Match 3 directory.
所以有一个第三场比赛的目录
And would anybody like to come demo it in class?
有没有人愿意来课堂上演示一下？
All right, [? Tony. ?] Come on up.
好的 [？托尼 ？]上来吧
All right, so whenever you're ready, go ahead, and just hit Return here.
好的 只要你准备好了 继续 然后点击这里的Return
[GAME MUSIC PLAYING]
[游戏音乐播放]
All right, and so this is my implementation of Match 3.
好的 这就是我实现的Match 3
It uses a different set of tiles.
它使用了一套不同的瓷砖
We have things that are moving over time.
我们有一些东西正在随着时间的推移而变化
It's arrow key based.
它是基于箭头键的
So if you press Enter on any tile, you can flip it with another tile.
因此 如果在任何瓷砖上按Enter键 就可以用另一个瓷砖翻转它
It doesn't have to be a match, in this case.
在这种情况下 它不一定是匹配的
So you can-- yeah.
所以你可以--是的
Yeah, you kind of got an unlucky board.
是啊 你的冲浪板有点不走运
There, at the very bottom, I see there's a few that--
在那里 在最下面 我看到有几个--
some brown ones you can match together.
一些棕色的 你可以搭配在一起
So once you match them together, the tiles come down to repopulate.
因此 一旦你将它们匹配在一起 瓷砖就会下来重新填充
You get new tiles up top.
上面会有新的瓷砖
And so notice, we have a timer on the left as well.
所以请注意 我们在左边也有一个计时器
It's something that's counting down.
这是一些正在倒计时的东西
We'll see how this is actually done with the library we'll be using, as opposed
我们将看看我们将使用的库是如何实际完成的 而不是
to managing a counter variable keeping track of it over time.
涉及管理计数器变量 随着时间的推移跟踪它
A lot of games will actually implement it so you have to-- you can only,
很多游戏实际上会实现它 所以你必须--你只能
and this will be part of the assignment, actually,
事实上 这将是作业的一部分
where you can only move a tile if it creates a match.
只有在创建匹配的情况下 您才能移动瓷砖
In this case, there's a--
在这种情况下 有一个--
and we can see the timer counting down, and then once you-- yeah,
我们可以看到计时器倒计时 然后一旦你--是的
if you don't get past the goal, there's a game over.
如果你没有越过球门 比赛就结束了
But thanks, [? Tony. ?] I appreciate it.
但还是谢谢你 [？托尼 ？]我很感激
AUDIENCE: No problem.
观众：没问题
SPEAKER 1: So that's the game in a nutshell.
演讲者1：简而言之 这就是游戏
And another thing I want to point out to is
我想指出的另一件事是
the transition, the white transitions, and then the level text.
转场、白色转场 然后是关卡文字
Those are all done with timers that we'll be using,
这些都是用我们将使用的定时器完成的
and tweens, which we'll be covering in class here
和青少年 我们将在这里的课堂上讨论
as some of our early examples.
作为我们早期的一些例子
But there's a lot of stuff that we haven't touched on, but also
但有很多东西我们还没有触及 但也
a lot that we have.
我们拥有的东西很多
It uses sprites, and a sprite sheet, and we've done that thing before.
它使用精灵和精灵薄片 我们以前也做过这样的事情
We chop up a sprite sheet, and then take out the whatever individual quads
我们切碎一张精灵薄片 然后拿出任何一个四边形
you need, and draw them to the screen.
你需要的 并将它们吸引到屏幕上
Here's what our goal is, which is we have a title screen with Match 3,
这是我们的目标 那就是我们有一个带有第三场比赛的标题屏幕
start, and quit game in this case.
在这种情况下 开始和退出游戏
A little bit simpler.
稍微简单一点
No high scores this time just because we've already covered that,
这一次没有高分 因为我们已经讨论过了
but we also have a level screen.
但我们也有一个水平屏幕
It tells us what level we're on before we can actually play,
它告诉我们 在我们真正开始比赛之前 我们处于什么水平
and there will be a transition box with text in it.
将会有一个带有文本的过渡框
It'll come down, stop, and then come down again.
它会掉下来 停下来 然后再下来
So almost like chain behavior, which we'll see how we implement that too.
所以几乎就像链行为 我们也会看到我们如何实现它
And then lastly, on the bottom there is our main game screen,
最后 在底部是我们的主游戏屏幕
where we have a level, a score, and then a goal.
我们有一个级别 一个比分 然后是一个进球
If you get the goal amount of points before the timer runs out,
如果你在计时器用完之前得到了目标点数
then you go to level 2, and level 3, and level 4,
然后你转到2级 3级 4级
and the score increases by a multiplied factor each time.
而且每次分数都会增加一个倍数
So the first thing I'd like to start talking about today
所以我今天要谈的第一件事
is how we actually get timer behavior using something a little bit more
我们实际上是如何使用更多的东西来获得计时器行为的
than just keeping track of some variable that we set to 0,
不仅仅是跟踪一些我们设置为0的变量
and then adding dt to it every update.
然后在每次更新时都添加DT
There's a better way to do that, but first, why don't we
有一个更好的方法来做到这一点 但首先 我们为什么不
go ahead, and look at timer0.
继续 看一下定时器0
And so what I'm going to do is go into the timer0 directory.
所以我要做的是进入timer0目录
I'm going run it, and we can see here, in the middle of the screen,
我要运行它 我们可以在屏幕中央看到
just a very simple--
只是一个非常简单的--
just a label that just says timer, and then x seconds,
只是一个标签 上面只写着计时器 然后是x秒
where obviously the x is incrementing over time every second.
很明显 x每秒都在随时间递增
So a crude way, what would be an easy way to implement this?
那么 粗略地说 有什么简单的方法可以实现这一点呢？
AUDIENCE: Do you like [INAUDIBLE] random in Flappy Bird [INAUDIBLE] randomizer
观众：你喜欢Flappy Bird中的随机数吗？
[INAUDIBLE] if you just keep track of your delta prime
[听不见]如果你只记录你的德尔塔质数
and add it to some variable outside [INAUDIBLE] you do something else?
然后把它加到外部的某个变量上 你还做了别的什么？
You could even just display the variable [INAUDIBLE]..
您甚至可以只显示变量[INAUDIBLE]..
SPEAKER 1: Yes.
演讲者1：是的
So the response was keep some variable that you modify with dt in update,
因此响应是保留一些您在更新中使用dT修改变量
or display the variable.
或显示变量
Yeah, that's definitely a way.
是啊 这绝对是一种方法
Did you have--
你有没有--
AUDIENCE: Yeah, I was just going to say, keep a float variable,
观众：是的 我只是想说 保持一个浮动变量
and constantly add a dt to it, and display it,
并不断地向它添加一个DT 并显示它
but display the truncated version.
但显示截断的版本
SPEAKER 1: Yeah.
演讲者1：是的
So keep a float variable, but just truncate the delta time off of it.
所以保持一个浮点型变量 但只截断它的增量时间
You could do that, definitely.
你当然可以这么做
We'll take a look here as to actually how I did do it.
我们将在这里看看我是如何做到的
It's very similar to that.
这与此非常相似
This is the wrong directory, though.
不过 这不是一个正确的目录
So it's in timer0 in main.
所以它在main中的定时器0中
So we do have a variable.
所以我们确实有一个变量
So the current second here, which we are going to keep track of 0, 1, 2.
所以这里的当前秒 我们将跟踪它 1 2
Lua doesn't really have the notion of truncate a float
Lua实际上没有截断浮点数的概念
because when you take a number that's floating point,
因为当你取一个浮点数时
and you make it into a string, you actually
你把它做成一串 你实际上
have to do string substitution on it where
必须在它的以下位置进行字符串替换
you use a function called g sub to take off the last part manually
您可以使用一个名为g SUB的函数来手动去除最后一部分
because it doesn't really differentiate between ints and floats.
因为它并没有真正区分整型和浮点型
It just has a number data type.
它只有一个数字数据类型
But we can do this by just keeping track of
但我们可以通过跟踪
whether or not we've passed a certain length of time
不管我们是否已经度过了一定的时间长度
because we know dt is given to us in seconds.
因为我们知道DT是在几秒钟内给我们的
We can just add to our variable, and then every time we've
我们只需添加变量 然后每次我们
gone over 1, because it gives us--
超过1 因为它给了我们--
it gives you usually like .013, whatever 1/60 or approximately 1/60 of a second
它通常会给你0.013 无论是1/60或大约1/60秒
is.
是
Once our timer-- we're going to keep a timer variable-- equals 1,
一旦计时器--我们将保持一个计时器变量--等于1
we'll just increment current second by 1,
我们只需将当前秒递增1
and then we'll set that timer back to 0, and then
然后我们将计时器设置回0 然后
we'll just repeat over, and over again.
我们只是一遍又一遍地重复
We'll actually use modulus so in case we go slightly over 1 second,
我们将实际使用模数 所以如果我们略高于1秒
we can account for that.
我们可以解释这一点
We do that here.
我们这里就是这么做的
So second timer gets second timer plus delta time,
所以第二个计时器得到第二个计时器加上增量时间
and then if it's greater than 1.
然后如果它大于1
So if a full second has elapsed, just increment current second,
因此 如果已经过了整整一秒 只需增加当前秒
and then modulo a second timer by 1.
然后以1为模对第二个计时器取模
And Lua is a little different in that most languages only let
Lua有一点不同 因为大多数语言只允许
you modulo something if it's an integer, but since there is no differentiation,
如果某件事是一个整数 你可以对它取模 但因为没有微分
you can actually modulo floats, and you'll
你可以对浮点数取模 你会
get the floating point value leftover.
获取剩余的浮点值
And so that's the basic way of actually doing that,
这就是真正做到这一点的基本方式
but there's a couple of things wrong with it.
但它有几个地方不对劲
So does anybody want to suggest what is potentially bad or unscalable
那么 有没有人想建议一下什么是潜在的糟糕或不可扩展的
about this kind of approach?
关于这种方法？
Well, I'll show you timer1 so we can maybe
好的 我给你看计时器 这样我们就可以
get a sense of how this could kind of get out of hand pretty quickly.
让我们了解一下 这件事是如何很快失控的
So let's say-- first, I'll run timer1.
让我们假设--首先 我将运行计时器1
So let's go into timer1 here, and notice now we have five labels.
让我们进入计时器1 注意现在我们有五个标签
They're running at different intervals.
它们以不同的间隔运行
The first timer, it's incrementing every 1 second,
第一个计时器每1秒递增一次
the second timer is incrementing every 4 seconds,
第二定时器每4秒递增一次
the third one is incrementing every 4 seconds, and then so on, 3, and then 2.
第三个是每4秒递增一次 然后依次递增 3 然后2
So if we wanted to do the same approach that we just did,
因此 如果我们想要做我们刚刚做过的相同的方法
this is what we would do.
这就是我们要做的
We have five variables, five timers.
我们有五个变量 五个定时器
Because we want to keep track of whether or not
因为我们想要记录一下
something's gone over more than just one second,
不只是一秒钟的事情
it's not super easy to just put this all in a table,
仅仅把这些都放在一张桌子上并不是一件非常容易的事情
and iterate over it, and use your iteration logic to do that.
并对其进行迭代 并使用您的迭代逻辑来执行此操作
We actually, because they're in some sort of random, who knows what order,
我们实际上 因为它们是某种随机的 谁知道是什么顺序
timer2 takes 2 seconds, OK, timer3 takes 4 seconds, timer4 takes 3, and then 2,
定时器2用2秒 好的 定时器3用4秒 定时器4用3 然后2
you have to unmanageably keep all of this in separate variables.
您必须以难以管理的方式将所有这些都放在单独的变量中
[? Yes, Tony ?]
[?什么事 托尼？]
AUDIENCE: Couldn't you just use one second timer, or even one variable,
观众：你能不能只用一秒钟的计时器 甚至一个变量
and then just in the display [INAUDIBLE]
然后就在显示器上[INAUDIBLE]
SPEAKER 1: You could.
演讲者1：你可以
Yeah, in this case, you could.
是啊 在这种情况下 你可以
Again, Lua's display, it's a little bit funky when you--
再说一次 Lua的展示 当你--
you have to do g sub, and some weird string stuff,
你得做g潜水艇 还有一些奇怪的弦乐动作
but yes, you could do that.
但是的 你可以做到这一点
AUDIENCE: Couldn't you just do modulo 1, and then take that value as a string?
观众：难道你不能只做模1 然后把这个值作为一个字符串吗？
Is that the equivalent of truncating?
这相当于截断吗？
SPEAKER 1: Modulo 1 would still give you the floating point value
扬声器1：模1仍然会给你浮点值
because there's only one number type.
因为只有一种数字类型
So if we modulo 1.00157 by 1, we'd get 0.00157.
所以如果我们把1.00157除以1 我们会得到0.00157
AUDIENCE: Oh.
观众：哦
OK.
好的
If you subtracted from that value, from I don't know.
如果你从那个值中减去 我不知道
So it's a value minus the value of modulo 1, I guess.
所以我想这是一个减去模1的值
SPEAKER 1: So yeah.
演讲者1：是的
It was proposed that we've used modulo, and we could.
有人建议我们使用模数 而且我们也可以
In short, we could, but what if we're not just
简而言之 我们可以 但如果我们不仅仅是
printing a value to the screen.
将值打印到屏幕上
What if we have 10 different things, like 10 different creatures that
如果我们有10种不同的东西 比如10种不同的生物
are all doing different things over time,
随着时间的推移做着不同的事情
and we don't necessarily want to have to keep a timer for each,
我们不一定要为每个人都保留一个计时器
and every one of those things.
以及每一件事
In a simple example like this, yeah, there's probably a--
在这样一个简单的例子中 是的 可能有一个--
on purpose, it's also a little bit convoluted just
故意说 它也有点复杂 只是
to illustrate the problem.
来说明这个问题
But yes, there are shortcuts for this, but the fundamental problem
但没错 这是有捷径的 但根本的问题是
is how can we get rid of having five different timers for something?
我们如何才能摆脱对某件事有五个不同的计时器？
And by the way, I'll go to the next slide.
顺便说一句 我将转到下一张幻灯片
Timer0, the simple way.
计时器0 简单的方法
Timer1, the ugly way.
计时器1 丑陋的方式
Timer2 is the clean way that I found using this ecosystem.
Timer2是我发现的使用这个生态系统的干净方式
There's a wonderful library, and you could implement this yourself.
有一个很棒的库 你可以自己实现它
The fundamental idea is have a global timer
基本的想法是有一个全局计时器
object that then manages all of these different things going
对象 然后管理所有这些不同的事情
on using the power of what I alluded to earlier, anonymous functions,
在使用我之前提到的匿名函数的能力时
and I'll show you how that works.
我将向你们展示这是如何运作的
So in main.lua of timer2, we have a set of intervals.
因此 在定时器2的Main.Lua中 我们有一组间隔
We have a set of counters.
我们有一套柜台
And then what we're doing here is we're just saying for i gets 1 to 5,
然后我们在这里做的是 我们只是说我得到了1到5
we're calling a function call timer.every.
我们正在调用一个函数调用定时器
So if you're familiar with JavaScript programming,
因此 如果您熟悉JavaScript编程
there's a set interval function which lets
有一个设定的区间函数 它让
you do something every length of time.
你每隔一段时间就会做一件事
So first of all, timer is just a library.
所以 首先 定时器只是一个库
We've just required it here.
我们只是在这里需要它
It's part of the knife ecosystem, and then
它是刀子生态系统的一部分 然后
here, we have a couple of functions, timer.every, and timer.after
在这里 我们有几个函数：timer.each和timer.After
that we'll use.
我们会用到的
Well, basically, what it does is you give it
基本上 它所做的就是你把它
a length of time-- timer.every seconds.
一段时间--计时器 每秒钟
It's in seconds, and you can give it fractional seconds.
它是以秒为单位的 你可以给它几秒
You're passing in just a function here, just an anonymous function.
您在这里传递的只是一个函数 一个匿名函数
It doesn't have a name, but because Lua, and a lot of dynamic languages
它没有名字 但因为Lua和许多动态语言
treat functions as first class citizens, as it
把职能当做一等公民对待 就像对待
called, because they are data types, you can just pass them into functions.
调用 因为它们是数据类型 所以只需将它们传递给函数即可
This allows us to do behavior like this that would otherwise
这使得我们可以像这样做 否则就不会这样做
be a little bit tricky to do.
做起来有点棘手
We can just say after this block of time,
我们可以说 在这段时间之后
assuming we've built some structure that is probably just storing
假设我们已经建立了一些结构 它可能只是存储
a table with a bunch of things that have a length of time in them,
一张桌子 里面有一堆东西 里面有一段时间
just call this block of code later.
只需稍后调用这段代码
It's called a callback function.
它被称为回调函数
We're just going to call it back, and then we're just going to do this.
我们只是要把它打回去 然后我们就这么做
We're going to say counters i gets counters i plus 1.
我们会说计数器I得到计数器i加1
So we have all of these intervals, and all of these counters.
所以我们有所有这些间隔 和所有这些计数器
So it will just, basically, manage that for us,
因此 基本上 它将为我们管理这一点
and now we don't have five variables.
现在我们没有五个变量了
You do have to set whatever you want those to be.
你确实必须设置你想要的任何东西
That's your that's your primitive at this point.
这是你的 这是你的原始人
You just need the lengths of time, depending on your problem.
你只需要时间的长短 取决于你的问题
In this case, that's all we need.
在这种情况下 这就是我们所需要的
You might need more than that, depending on what you want to do with timer.
您可能需要更多 这取决于您想要用Timer做什么
But in this case, we just want to increment in value over time.
但在这种情况下 我们只想随着时间的推移增加价值
So keep counters, and then just keep track of the intervals,
所以记下计数器 然后记录下时间间隔
and then our code's gone from I don't know how many lines.
然后我们的代码就从我不知道有多少行
It was a lot larger--
它要大得多
I think was 96 lines, down to 98 lines, down to 70,
我认为是96行 减少到98行 减少到70行
and this is incredibly scalable.
这是令人难以置信的可伸缩性
If we wanted to add another one that's 8 for example,
例如 如果我们想要添加另一个8
we just need to add 8, and then that.
我们只需要加8 然后就是那个
I guess I'd have to do this as well.
我想我也得这么做
I gets 5 to 6, and then you want to-- the computer that requires me
我得到5到6个 然后你想--需要我的电脑
to off my user so I can make changes.
来关闭我的用户 这样我就可以进行更改
We'll just real quickly see if I didn't mess up.
我们很快就会知道我是不是搞砸了
And so yeah, basically we're deferring everything to timer now.
所以 是的 基本上我们现在把一切都推迟到Timer了
We get the exact same behavior, but a much smaller length of code.
我们得到了完全相同的行为 但代码长度要短得多
And the nice thing is it's very declarative.
好的是 它非常具有说明性
We can just say OK, every something seconds, I want this chunk of behavior
我们可以说 好的 每一秒 我想要这一大块行为
to happen.
会发生的
I don't have to see OK, I've got timers up here, I've got counters here.
我不需要看到好的 我在上面有计时器 我在这里有计数器
OK, down in my draw function, OK, I've got to draw all these.
好的 在我的DRAW函数中 好的 我必须画出所有这些
It's iterative, and it's declarative, and that's the ultimate goal.
它是迭代的 它是陈述性的 这是最终目标
And here, at the very bottom, it did actually work.
在这里 在最底层 它确实起到了作用
Now it's working every eight seconds, which is nice.
现在它每八秒工作一次 这很好
One, two, there we go.
一 二 开始了
Super easy to extend.
超级容易扩展
We're going to be using it a lot in this problem set,
我们将在这个习题集中大量使用它
and also in future lectures just because it's a lot easier than keeping
在未来的演讲中也是如此 只是因为这比保持
track of a bunch of counter variables.
追踪一堆反变数
And there's another function that we're seeing here--
我们在这里看到的还有另一个功能--
timer.after because sometimes you just want to wait a certain length of time.
计时器 之后 因为有时你只想等待一段时间
Maybe you have every 1 second for 5 seconds you want a bomb to tick,
也许你每隔1秒就有5秒的时间想要一个炸弹滴答作响
and then after 5 seconds, you want it to blow up,
然后5秒后 你想让它爆炸
and you could also model that with another function that we'll see soon,
你也可以用我们很快会看到的另一个函数来模拟它
but these are probably the two core time-based functions.
但这可能是两个基于时间的核心函数
And you can go here to this URL able to see the knife library.
你可以在这里访问这个URL 可以看到刀库
There's a bunch of modules that are really nice.
有一大堆非常好的模块
We just happen to be using timer, and it's
我们只是碰巧使用了定时器 它是
tween, and every after functions primarily in this problem.
补间 以及之后的每一个功能主要是在这个问题上
But we'll use another one called the event in the Zelda [? p-set, ?] where
但我们将在塞尔达使用另一个名为Event的词[？P-集合 ？]哪里
we actually look at how to dispatch events, and triggers, and stuff,
我们实际上研究了如何调度事件、触发器和其他东西
and to prevent us from checking every frame.
并防止我们检查每一帧画面
Oh, what do we have to do?
哦 我们要做什么？
If some wall is broken, this frame, then do this.
如果某个墙被打破了 这个框架 然后这样做
We can just dispatch an event that we blow up a wall.
我们可以只调度一个事件我们炸了一堵墙
We'll get to that.
我们会讲到那个的
Any questions at all about how those two models differ, and how they work?
对于这两种模式的不同之处以及它们的工作原理 有什么疑问吗？
OK, cool.
好的 酷
So the next thing I want to look at-- so we can tie that back into also,
接下来我想看看--这样我们就可以把它联系起来
real quick, if we want.
非常快 如果我们想的话
Match 3-- whoops, and then there's a timer that's
第三场比赛--哎呀 还有一个计时器
manipulating the text on the screen.
操纵屏幕上的文本
All of those letters in the-- this is in the start state of the game code.
所有字母都在--这是游戏代码的开始状态
All of those letters have a color associated with them,
所有这些字母都有一种与之相关的颜色
but they're on a timer so that after every 0.075 seconds,
但它们是有计时器的 所以每隔0.075秒
they'll go to another color, and to another color.
它们会变成另一种颜色 再变成另一种颜色
And so we don't have to keep track of every letter's
这样我们就不必记录每一封信
individual color, and a timer for it.
单独的颜色 以及它的计时器
We can just change them all.
我们可以把它们全部换掉
If we start the game, something else that's on a timer, the timer,
如果我们开始游戏 计时器上的其他东西 计时器
actually, there, which is just decrementing some value.
实际上 在那里 这只是减少了一些价值
Every one second, decrement timer by 1, and that's it,
每一秒 将计时器减1 就是这样
and we don't have to keep any-- we don't have to say anything more than just
我们不需要保留任何东西--我们不需要说什么 除了
that, and that's what's really nice about using that kind of model.
这就是使用这种模型的真正好处
So another thing that you probably also noticed, and I'll run it again,
还有一件事 你们可能也注意到了 我会再讲一遍
is this fade out, and fade in, and also that animation.
这是淡出 淡入 还有那个动画
Those are things that are happening over time.
这些都是随着时间的推移而发生的事情
We don't actually-- we can just sort of manipulate them.
我们实际上并不--我们可以在某种程度上操纵它们
We can keep track of some sort of counter for it.
我们可以跟踪它的某种计数器
We can also just say over this length of time, change this value to this value,
我们也可以说在这段时间内 将这个值更改为这个值
and that's a much easier way to model the problem mentally.
这是一种更容易对问题进行心理建模的方法
And so we'll illustrate that.
因此 我们将对此进行说明
First, I'm going to go to tween0.
首先 我要去tween0
So tween0 is the simple way to do something.
所以tween0是做某事的简单方法
So I'm going to illustrate tweening here with Flappy Bird just going
所以我要在这里用Flappy Bird来说明补间
left to right.
从左到右
So up there, that's what happens when you print out the number, by the way,
所以在上面 这就是当你打印数字时发生的事情 顺便说一句
just by default.
只是默认情况下
And so if you wanted to truncate it, yeah, you
因此 如果你想截断它 是的 你
could just g sub the first two, I guess, depending on how large it is,
我想 根据它的大小 能不能把前两个放在一起
and that would have the effect of displaying it as just an integer.
这将产生仅将其显示为整数的效果
But we can see that over two seconds, we've had--
但我们可以看到 在两秒钟的时间里 我们有--
and there's a little bit of overlap just because delta time can
有一点重叠只是因为增量时间可以
go a little bit over two seconds when you're adding to it because it just
两秒多一点 当你加到它的时候 因为它只是
adds whatever length of time as a float has elapsed since the last frame.
添加自上一帧以来浮点经过的时间长度
In this case, we're just adding it until it's greater than or equal to 2.
在本例中 我们只是将其相加 直到它大于或等于2
So in this case, we went 0.01 over 2 by the time that actually ended.
所以在这种情况下 我们在实际结束的时候是0.01除以2
Some iterations will be less than that.
有些迭代会比这更少
So this one will be--
所以这一次将是--
yeah, see, that one was less than 2.01.
是啊 看 那个还不到2.01
It just depends on your computer, and your specs.
这取决于你的电脑和你的规格
But Flappy Bird starts on the very left.
但Flappy Bird从最左边开始
So he's got an x-coordinate, and then at the very end,
所以他有一个x坐标 然后在最后
he's got another x-coordinate.
他有另一个X坐标
So the simple solution is what?
那么简单的解决方案是什么？
We know that we want this to elapse over two seconds.
我们知道我们希望这段时间超过两秒
So what we can do is I'm going to pull up tween0.
所以我们可以做的是 我要把tween0拉出来
And MOVE_DURATION here, it's a constant of 2 seconds just
在这里 它是2秒的常量
for the sake of this example.
出于这个例子的考虑
A sprite here, just a simple image.
这里是一个精灵 只是一个简单的图像
I'm putting everything in one code file this time, as opposed to breaking it
这一次我把所有东西都放在一个代码文件中 而不是破坏它
out into subclasses just for simplicity because these are such small examples.
为了简单起见 我们将其划分为子类 因为这些都是非常小的示例
But we're setting it's x and y.
但我们将其设置为x和y
Oh, and this is another Lua trick, by the way.
哦 顺便说一句 这是另一个Lua的把戏
You can assign two variables to two values using a comma here.
您可以在此处使用逗号将两个变量赋给两个值
So flappyX comma flappyY gets 0, and then VIRTUAL_HEIGHT
因此flappyX逗号flappyY得到0 然后是VIRTUAL_HEIGH
divided by 2 minus 8.
除以2减8
Setting this x to 0, we have a timer here, and then it's end x.
将这个x设置为0 我们在这里有一个计时器 然后它就是x的终点
So we want it to end at the end of the screen.
所以我们希望它在屏幕的末尾结束
So we're going to say virtual width minus his width, an then
所以我们会说虚拟宽度减去他的宽度 然后
the usual boilerplate for getting a project set to go.
这是让项目开始进行的常见样板
If it's less than the move duration-- so if timer is 0 going up to 2,
如果它小于移动持续时间--所以如果计时器是0升到2
but it's not quite 2 yet, we're going to add dt to it, and then we're going to,
但还不到2 我们要加上dT 然后我们要
basically, assign it to either the lowest of end x,
基本上 将其分配给末端x中的最低者
so it will never go higher than end x, or end x times the ratio of timer
所以它永远不会高于结束x 或者结束x乘以计时器的比率
over move duration.
超过移动持续时间
So timer over move duration, if it's less than 2,
所以计时器超过移动持续时间 如果它小于2
that's going to be some value, some fractional amount less than 1.
这将是一些值 一些分数小于1
So it's going to basically just scale it,
因此 它基本上只是按比例进行扩展
depending on how far we've moved the timer between 0 and 2.
这取决于我们将计时器移到0到2之间的距离
So just a scaling operation.
因此 这只是一次规模操作
This happens to only work in the context of moving something from left to right,
这只在从左向右移动物体的情况下才起作用
or from 0 to something else, but it's a crude, basic way of illustrating
或者从0到其他值 但这是一种粗略的、基本的说明方法
a very basic tween operation.
一个非常基本的补间操作
That's what it essentially is.
这就是它的本质
It's a multiplier of some ratio of how much time has passed,
它是时间流逝时间的乘数
versus how much time we're actually looking to elapse.
而不是我们实际期待的流逝时间
And that has the effect, once again, of just--
而这又一次产生了这样的效果--
it's scaling the ratio because it's timer over moved duration.
它正在调整比率 因为它的计时器超过了移动的持续时间
It's something over 2, but it's not quite 2 over 2.
它是大于2的东西 但不完全是2除以2
Until it gets 2 over 2, and it's 1, then end x times 1 is going to be end x.
直到它等于2除以2 并且是1 那么end x乘以1就是end x
But before that, it's going to be some fraction of end x between 0 and end x.
但在此之前 它将是末端x的某个分数 介于0和末端x之间
So it has the effect of giving us a very basic tween, but it's a little bit--
所以它的效果是给了我们一个非常基本的补丁 但它有一点--
we have a little bit to manage here.
我们这里有一点事情要处理
It doesn't really feel super clean.
感觉并不是很干净
Do you guys have any questions about how this works?
你们对这是怎么回事有什么疑问吗？
OK.
好的
So we're going to go here.
所以我们要从这里开始
So first of all, any thoughts about how that might not be super scalable,
因此 首先 有没有想过这可能不是超级可扩展的
looking back at the last example?
回过头来看最后一个例子？
AUDIENCE: I guess like the situation before,
观众：我想就像以前的情况一样
getting a lot of objects moving on the screen.
让很多物体在屏幕上移动
SPEAKER 1: Yeah, and what if your index is different for every single one?
演讲者1：是的 如果你的索引对于每个人来说都是不同的呢？
Then you have kind of a mess.
然后你就会有一团乱麻
What if we had something like this?
如果我们有这样的东西呢？
You don't want to keep track of an end to x.
您不会想要跟踪x的结尾
They all happened to have the same end x,
它们碰巧都有相同的末端x
but notice they're moving at different rates.
但请注意 它们的移动速度不同
They're all moving at some sort of random amount.
它们都在以某种随机的数量移动
AUDIENCE: How many are there?
观众：一共有几个？
SPEAKER 1: There's 1,000.
演讲者1：有1000个
We could go crazier if we wanted.
如果我们愿意 我们可以变得更疯狂
This is a fun thing to do, is stress testing.
这是一件有趣的事情 就是压力测试
So if I go to tween1, and I go to main, timer max is 10.
所以如果我转到Tween1 然后转到Main 最大计时器是10
So we're saying that the longest possible time
所以我们的意思是 尽可能长的时间
any bird can take to get from left to right is going be 10 seconds.
任何一只鸟从左到右都需要10秒
So right here, we're using a table based approach here.
因此 在这里 我们使用基于表的方法
We're actually keeping track of 1,000 birds, and we're saying,
我们实际上在跟踪1000只鸟 我们说
OK, here's an empty table from 1 to 1,000.
好的 这里有一张从1到1,000的空桌
Add a new bird, and in this case, we're not adding a bird object, or anything.
添加一只新的鸟 在本例中 我们不会添加鸟对象或任何东西
It's just a table.
这只是一张桌子
They all start x equals 0, left side.
它们都是从x=0开始的 左侧
Their y is random.
他们的y是随机的
So they can be anywhere between the top and the bottom of the screen.
因此 它们可以位于屏幕顶部和底部之间的任何位置
So VIRTUAL_HEIGHT minus 24.
因此 虚拟高度减去24
24 happens to be the height of the sprite,
24正好是精灵的高度
and I should have probably put Flappy sprite get height right there.
我应该把Flappy Sprite Get Height放在那里
And then rate, they're all going to have their own rate.
然后是利率 他们都会有自己的利率
So rate gets math.random.
所以Rate得到了数学 随机的
Math.random without a value passed into it
Math.随机数 没有传入任何值
gives you a fractional value between 0 and 0.999999.
为您提供一个介于0和0.999999之间的小数值
What this has the effect of doing is math.random with just two values,
这样做的效果是数学 只有两个值的随机数
if you pass in 10 and 50, it's going to give you 10 to 50,
如果你通过10和50 它会给你10到50
but they're always going to be integer values.
但它们始终是整数值
You can't say like 10.0 and 50.0, and assume that it
你不能说像10.0和50.0 然后假设它
will know what you're talking about.
都会知道你在说什么
It's just going to be integers.
它只会是整数
So if you give it one value, it will know.
因此 如果你给它一个值 它就会知道
OK, you're asking me for a float between 0 and 0.999999.
好的 你是在要求我的浮点数介于0和0.999999之间
That's going to act as the fractional part of whatever value we
这将作为我们的价值的小数部分
might want to generate using a math.random with a value passed in.
可能希望使用传入了值的math.Ranb来生成
So here, we're saying OK, math.random, TIMER_MAX minus 1.
所以在这里 我们说好的 数学 随机 定时器_最大值减1
So TIMER_MAX is 9.
因此 Timer_Max为9
So our TIMER_MAX is 10, sorry.
所以我们的最大定时器是10 抱歉
So if we subtract 1 from that, this is math.random 10.
所以如果我们减去1 这就是数学 随机10
So we're going to get a value between 1 and 9.
所以我们将得到一个介于1和9之间的值
So TIMER_MAX minus 1 is 9.
因此Timer_Max减去1等于9
Sorry if I said 10.
如果我说的是10个 对不起
TIMER_MAX is 10, TIMER_MAX minus 1 is 9, but we're
Timer_Max是10 Timer_Max减1是9 但是
adding math.random, some fractional amount.
加上数学 随机的 一些分数
So whatever value we choose between 1--
所以无论我们在1之间选择什么值--
actually between-- yeah, between 1 and 9,
实际上在--是的 在1到9之间
it's going to be that value, point something.
它将是那个价值 指向一些东西
So this is how you get random--
所以这就是你如何变得随机的--
basically, at the end of the day, this is
基本上 在一天结束的时候 这是
how you get random floating point numbers in Lua and Love2D.
如何在Lua和Love2D中获得随机浮点数
Does that make sense?
这说得通吗？
Do you guys have questions about that?
你们对此有什么问题吗？
AUDIENCE: So your final rate could be anywhere from 0 to--
观众：所以你的最终比率可能是从0到--
SPEAKER 1: Final rate is going to be anywhere from 1-- in this case from,
演讲者1：最终的速率是从1到--在这个例子中
1 to 9.999999.
1%到9.999999
If we wanted it to be 0, we could do that,
如果我们希望它是0 我们可以这样做
and that'll give us the effect of taking whatever we get, and subtracting 1.
这将给我们带来一个效果 就是取我们得到的任何东西 然后减去1
So now it will be between 0 and 8.999999.
所以现在它将在0到8.999999之间
And if we did this--
如果我们这样做--
AUDIENCE: Couldn't each math.random end up at 0?
观众：难道每个数学随机数都不能以0结束吗？
SPEAKER 1: No, because math.random, if you pass in a value,
演讲者1：不 因为数学随机 如果你传入一个值
it'll always do from 1 to some value.
它总是从1到某个值
The question was will math.random give you 0 if you pass in a value?
问题是 如果您传入一个值 Math.Random会给您0吗？
And math.random, by default, gives you between 1 and something else.
而在默认情况下 math.Random会给出1和其他值之间的值
And so that's why we do this.
这就是我们这么做的原因
That's not why we do this.
这不是我们这么做的原因
We do this to add the fractional part so that we can get
我们这样做是为了添加分数部分 这样我们就可以得到
fractional floats between some value.
分数浮动在某个值之间
But yeah, if you wanted it to be between 0, and something else,
但没错 如果你想让它介于0和其他值之间
you would just subtract 1 from the final result
你只需从最终结果中减去1
because we know that we're always going to get from 1 to some value.
因为我们知道我们总是会得到从1到某个值
If you minus from 1, you will never go below 0.
如果你从1减去 你永远不会低于0
It will always be 0 to something else, and then in that case,
它总是从0到其他值 然后在这种情况下
we probably would just take off the minus 1
我们可能只会去掉负1
from TIMER_MAX so that it will be between 0 and 9.999999 in this case.
从TIMER_MAX开始 因此在本例中将介于0和9.999999之间
But as a design decision, I made it so that we would always
但作为一个设计决定 我这样做是为了让我们总是
have at least a rate of 1 because then it
至少有一个比率1 因为这样它就
could get really, really slow if it's like 0.005 or something like that.
如果气温在0.005左右 可能会变得非常非常慢
You wouldn't want that.
你不会想要这样的
It would take ages.
这将需要很长一段时间
OK, so we have a timer.
好的 我们有一个计时器
We're not using knife.timer in this case yet.
在这种情况下 我们还没有使用knife.Timer
Basically, in update, we're just saying as long as timer max is less than--
基本上 在更新中 我们只是说只要计时器最大值小于--
timer is less than timer max.
计时器小于最大计时器
This update logic will only run as long as we haven't gone over timer max.
只有当我们没有超过最大计时器时 这个更新逻辑才会运行
Increment it, and then for each bird, basically, we're
增加它 然后对于每一只鸟 基本上 我们是
doing the same thing that we did before, except we're using
做我们以前做过的事情 只是我们用了
that bird's rate as the scale factor.
以那只鸟的速率作为比例因子
Yeah, the denominator of that ratio, and that
是的 这个比率的分母 就是
will have the effect of multiplying all of those birds
将会使所有这些鸟类成倍增加
individually, based on their own rate, rather than
个别 基于他们自己的利率 而不是
some global rate, if that makes sense.
一些全球利率 如果这是有意义的话
And then here, we're just drawing all of them at their own x and y.
然后在这里 我们只是用它们自己的x和y来画它们
And just again, we're just storing birds are just
再说一次 我们只是在储存鸟类
a table with a few variables in this case.
在本例中是包含几个变量的表
Just a very simple shell, and it has the effect of--
这只是一个非常简单的外壳 它的效果是--
oh, and one thing I wanted to do is just add a 0 there.
哦 我想做的一件事就是在那里加一个0
I've got to do this every time because I didn't
我每次都要这么做 因为我没有
set my permissions appropriately.
适当设置我的权限
But now there's going to be 10,000 birds.
但现在将有10,000只鸟
So let's see how this looks.
所以让我们来看看这是什么样子
So it looks pretty similar, actually, but it's a little more condensed now.
所以它看起来很相似 实际上 但现在它更浓缩了
I don't notice a frame rate drop.
我没有注意到帧速率下降
If we wanted, we could go down to love.draw, and love.graphics.printf
如果我们愿意 我们可以去love.raw和love.graph ics.print tf
at FPS, and then to string, love.timer.getFPS, and then
在FPS 然后到字符串 love.timer.getFPS 然后
let's set it to 4, and then VIRTUAL_HEIGHT minus 16,
让我们将其设置为4 然后虚拟高度减去16
and then got to do this again.
然后又得再来一次
This should have the effect of giving us our frame rate.
这应该具有为我们提供帧速率的效果
So we can really stress test this, and see what the--
所以我们真的可以进行压力测试 看看--
oh.
噢
I made a mistake.
我犯了一个错
OK, let's see.
好的 让我想想
What did I do?
我做了什么？
Push.start.
推啊 开始啊
I'm guessing I missed a--
我猜我错过了一个...
yeah, I missed a--
是啊 我错过了一个...
do that, and then that, and then save it again.
这样做 然后这样做 然后再保存一次
Sorry about that.
真对不起
There won't be too many of these edits, but I figured
不会有太多这样的编辑 但我想
this would be fun to illustrate.
这将是一个有趣的说明
So now, this should work.
因此 现在 这应该会奏效
Printf, so we have that.
Printf 所以我们有这个
Oh, right, and then it just needs to be print.
哦 对了 然后只需要打印出来就行了
It doesn't need to be printf.
它不需要是打印的
Got to save again.
又要存钱了
Sorry.
抱歉的
This will be worth it, I hope.
我希望这将是值得的
There we go, 5160.
好了 5160
OK, it takes a couple of seconds.
好的 这需要几秒钟
It has to interpolate between the last couple of times
它必须在最后几次之间进行内插
that it's pulled for frames, and when you start up,
它是为画框拉的 当你启动时
it doesn't have the data it needs.
它没有所需的数据
So 10,000, easy.
所以 一万 很容易
Let's do like a million.
让我们做一百万吧
So we have 10,000, 100,000, a million.
所以我们有10,000,100,000,100万
I really got to change those permissions.
我真的要更改这些权限
Getting good at practicing my password, though.
不过 我越来越擅长练习我的密码了
Going to go ahead, and do that.
去吧 去做那件事
Ooh.
哦 哦
Oh, my laptop is suffering.
哦 我的笔记本电脑坏了
Oh man, but they're all moving independent of frame rate.
天哪 但它们都是独立于帧速率移动的
This is just a testament to how powerful delta time is.
这只是三角洲时间有多强大的证明
They all move there after 10 seconds.
他们都在10秒后移动到那里
We've got to 10.6 seconds, which is not good.
我们还有10.6秒 这不是很好
That means that's how long passed between the last frame,
这意味着这是最后一帧之间经过的时间
but my laptop clearly can not handle a million birds on the screen,
但我的笔记本电脑显然不能处理屏幕上的一百万只鸟
but it can handle 10,000, or maybe even 100,000.
但它可以处理10,000 甚至100,000
And that's just a fun way--
这只是一种有趣的方式--
a fun thing to do.
这是一件有趣的事情
In general, when you want to stress test your game,
通常 当您想要对您的游戏进行压力测试时
just put the frames per second on, and just go nuts.
只需设置每秒帧数 然后就可以疯狂了
Just add a lot of stuff.
只是添加了很多东西
Just see what your computer is capable of because you
只要看看你的电脑有什么能力 因为你
can find new, fun things that way, I guess, and maybe just
我想 这样可以发现新的、有趣的东西 也许只是
see how good your code is too.
看看你的代码也有多好
So tween0, simple way.
所以Tween0 简单的方法
We have just variables, and one counter.
我们只有变量和一个计数器
No tables or anything.
没有桌子之类的
Tween2 is a good way for if we have a lot of things
如果我们有很多东西 Tween2是一个很好的方法
that we want to manipulate over time.
我们想要随着时间的推移来操纵
But what if now we want some of them to change
但如果现在我们想要其中的一些改变呢
their opacity over time or something?
他们随着时间的推移而变得不透明还是什么？
It starts to get a little bit more complicated.
事情开始变得有点复杂了
And this is, by the way, I should've put this earlier in the code,
顺便说一句 我应该早点把这个放在代码里
but this is the knife library is responsible for timer,
但这是刀库负责计时器
and a lot of other things that we'll be looking at,
以及我们将会看到的许多其他东西
and it's got a bunch of modules here listed--
它在这里列出了一系列模块--
behavior for state machines, which is like what
状态机的行为 这就像什么
we've been doing for state machines, but they have their own version of it.
我们一直在为状态机做准备 但它们有自己的版本
Knife.bind, so you can pre-bind arguments to functions,
Knife.ind 因此您可以将参数预绑定到函数
and create subfunction.
并创建子函数
It's called currying, but create subfunctions of other functions
它被称为Currying 但创建了其他函数的子函数
that have pre-determined variables.
它们有预先确定的变量
Knife.chain, we'll see, actually, how that can be used coming up later.
Knife.Chain 实际上 我们稍后会看到如何使用它
Convoke is for coroutines.
召集会是用于协作性的
We'll see coroutines in the context of Unity,
我们将在统一的背景下看到协程
but basically, they're functions that can pause their state for later.
但从根本上说 它们是可以暂停其状态以便稍后使用的函数
Knife.event we'll use in two weeks for Zelda,
Knife.我们将在两周内为塞尔达使用这一事件
maybe even next week if I can fit it in for Mario.
也许甚至是下周 如果我能为马里奥安排的话
Memoize is for memoization.
Memoize是用于记忆的
It's like a dynamic programming related thing.
这就像是与动态编程相关的事情
Serialized system.
序列化系统
System is going to be useful to know about in context of Unity as well.
在团结的背景下 了解系统也将是有用的
Unity uses an entity component system for much of its structure.
Unity的大部分结构使用实体组件系统
Knife.test, and then lastly, knife.timer,
Knife.test 最后是Knife.Timer
which is what we'll end up using, and this is probably my favorite library
这就是我们最终将使用的库 这可能是我最喜欢的库
that exists in the Love2D ecosystem.
存在于Love2D生态系统中
And so with that said, we'll look at tween2 now.
说到这里 我们现在来看看tween2
I'm going to go here into tween2, and so now we have not just movement, but also
我将进入第二节 所以现在我们不仅有运动 还有
their opacity.
他们的不透明
They all start at different opacity levels,
它们都从不同的不透明度级别开始
and we want to not only change their movement
我们不仅想改变他们的运动
over time, but also the opacity.
随着时间的推移 也是不透明的
So it would get a little bit trickier if we decided
所以如果我们决定 事情会变得更棘手
to do that with our current situation.
在我们目前的情况下做到这一点
Totally doable, but how would we go about changing, just right now,
完全可行 但我们现在该如何着手改变
their opacity just as is?
他们的不透明就像现在一样？
How do you change a spite's opacity?
你如何改变怨恨的不透明性？
AUDIENCE: The variable and the graphics [INAUDIBLE]
受众：变量和图形[INAUDIBLE]
SPEAKER 1: Is it a variable-- can you say that one more time?
演讲者1：这是一个变量吗--你能再说一遍吗？
AUDIENCE: I forget the exact function name,
听众：我忘记了确切的函数名称
but it's like love.graphics to put an image on the screen.
但这就像是把图像放在屏幕上的爱
SPEAKER 1: The love.graphics.draw.
演讲者1：The love.graph ics.Drag
AUDIENCE: Wasn't there an argument in that?
观众：这里面不是有争论吗？
SPEAKER 1: So it's actually not an argument to that function.
演讲者1：所以它实际上不是那个函数的参数
So I'll show you now.
所以我现在就给你们展示一下
So in order to draw something at some different opacity,
因此 为了在不同的不透明度下绘制一些东西
it's actually love.graphics.setcolor, and we do that here.
它实际上是love.graph ics.setcolor 我们在这里这样做
So recall that Love2D is a state machine, and how it draws things.
所以回想一下 Love2D是一个状态机 以及它是如何绘制事物的
You can basically set a color onto anything
你基本上可以给任何东西设置颜色
that you draw, whether it's a font, an image, or a shape.
无论是字体、图像还是形状 你都可以画出来
And if you just pass in 255, 255, 255, that's white.
如果你只传255,255,255 那就是白色
And then if you give it an opacity, which
然后如果你给它一个不透明的 这
is the fourth parameter, which is the alpha component of that,
是第四个参数 这是它的阿尔法分量
then that's how transparent it will be.
那么这就是它的透明度
And so we could have done this with other colors too.
所以我们也可以用其他颜色来做这件事
We could have done this with like if we wanted to tint it red,
我们可以这样做 如果我们想把它染成红色
and also have it be sort of transparent.
同时也要让它变得透明
We could do that if we just did 25500 bird.opacity.
如果我们只做25500只鸟 我们就能做到 不透明
But if you just want to manipulate opacity independent of--
但如果你只是想操纵不透明度 而不是--
or its transparency or its alpha independent of its color,
或者它的透明度或者它的阿尔法与它的颜色无关
and keep it the same exact color, you just do it white.
并保持相同的颜色 你只要把它弄白就行了
If you did it black, nothing would show up.
如果你做的是黑色的 什么都不会出现
Is that true, actually?
实际上 这是真的吗？
Let me verify that.
让我来验证一下
Pretty sure that's right, but I could be wrong.
我很确定这是对的 但我可能错了
I'm right, thankfully.
谢天谢地 我是对的
OK.
好的
That or they're just black, and there's a black background too.
或者它们只是黑色 而且也有黑色的背景
Do you have a question, [? Tony? ?]
你有什么问题吗？托尼？？]
AUDIENCE: No.
观众：没有
SPEAKER 1: Oh, OK.
演讲者1：哦 好的
So we'll take it on faith that that is correct.
因此 我们将相信这是正确的
And back to the gist of this example.
回到这个例子的主旨
We have TIMER_MAX again.
我们又有了Timer_Max
Actually, we really haven't changed much.
事实上 我们真的没有太大变化
What we have changed is we still have our birds.
我们改变的是 我们仍然有我们的鸟
We need to keep track of their x, of their y, of their rate.
我们需要跟踪他们的x、y和他们的比率
Well, not necessarily their rate.
嗯 不一定是他们的速度
Oh, well, their rate, yeah, because we're actually
哦 好吧 他们的价格 是啊 因为我们实际上
going to loop over each of these, and then create
循环遍历其中的每一个 然后创建
a timer between operations for them.
两次操作之间的计时器
And their opacity.
以及它们的不透明性
Oh right, they start with an opacity of 0,
哦 对了 它们以不透明度0开始
and faded to 55, regardless of their--
淡出到55岁 不管他们--
their opacity changes at the same rate as their x does.
它们的不透明度的变化速度与它们的x的变化速度相同
So the farther away, the longer they take,
因此 距离越远 他们需要的时间就越长
the slower they fade to fully opaque, and we see this here.
它们褪色到完全不透明的速度就越慢 我们在这里看到了这一点
So for k bird and pairs of birds.
所以对于k鸟和成对的鸟来说
So for every bird, we're just going to set a tween, and then this is tween.
所以 对于每一只鸟 我们只需设置一个吐温 然后这个就是吐温
So timer.tween is I think I have a slide on it here, right?
所以计时器 我想我在这上面有一张幻灯片 对吗？
A super cool useful function, super easy to use too, it
一个超酷有用的功能 也超好用 它
takes iteration just like timer.every, timer.after, and it takes a definition.
使用迭代 就像timer.each、timer.After一样 它需要一个定义
So in this case, it doesn't take an anonymous function
因此 在本例中 它不接受匿名函数
like the other ones did because we're not really
像其他人一样 因为我们并不是真的
saying I want to do some sort of undefined behavior
说我想做一些不确定的行为
over the course of this operation.
在这次行动的过程中
What I want to do is just change some values.
我想做的只是改变一些价值观
I want to interpolate them.
我想对它们进行插补
So what we're going to do is just pass in a-- this is the syntax for it.
所以我们要做的就是传入一个--这是它的语法
We pass in square brackets, the actual thing that we want to change.
我们传入方括号 这是我们想要更改的实际内容
In this case, I want to change bird.
在这种情况下 我想换一只鸟
I want bird to change in some way, and then
我想让小鸟以某种方式改变 然后
what I want it's values to change toward are these.
我希望它的价值观朝着以下方向改变
I want it's x to change to end x, and I want it's opacity to go to 255.
我希望x变为结束x 并且我希望它的不透明度变为255
And I wanted to do it over bird.rate, and so this bird.rate,
我想在小鸟身上做 Rate 所以这只小鸟 Rate
every bird is storing it.
每只鸟都在储存它
So for birds that got a rate of 2, then it's
所以 对于得到2分的鸟类来说 那么它就是
x is going to go to end x over the course of 2 seconds,
X将在2秒的过程中结束
and it's opacity is going to go to 255 over the course of 2 seconds.
它的不透明度将在2秒内达到255
And you can put as many things as you want, and as many--
你想放多少就放多少 放多少就放多少--
you can put as many variables here, and as many entities.
您可以在此处放置尽可能多的变量和实体
Entities being anything that you want to change that
实体是您想要更改的任何内容
has a field, any table-based or class-based structure.
具有字段、任何基于表或基于类的结构
You can pass any of those in here, and just tween them all at the same--
你可以把它们中的任何一个放在这里 然后把它们放在一起--
if they all have the same rate, and then just get that operation that way.
如果他们都有相同的比率 那么就用这种方式进行手术
And so that has the effect here of all we need to do is just add--
所以我们需要做的就是在这里添加--
it's like two lines of code, but now we've easily changed it so
它就像两行代码 但现在我们很容易地将其更改为
that we can just tween two things at once,
我们一次只能在两样东西之间做补丁
and that's the power of timer.tween, and we'll see that.
这就是定时器的力量 我们会看到的
So back to, actually, Match 3, if we want to look at that again.
所以回到第三场比赛 如果我们想再看一遍的话
This is a tween, that's a tween, that's a tween, and that's a tween.
这是补丁 那是补丁
So the white, the foreground there, is just a rectangle
所以白色 前景 只是一个矩形
that fills the whole screen.
它充满了整个屏幕
It's just a white rectangle.
它只是一个白色的长方形
I have it set to timer.tween opacity from 0 to 255.
我将其设置为定时器 补间不透明度从0到255
Before that gets called, if we go from the start to the begin game state,
在调用之前 如果我们从开始到开始游戏状态
and then if we go from at the beginning of the game state,
然后如果我们从游戏状态的开始
before the level text comes down, it's going from 255 to 0.
在级别文本下降之前 它将从255降到0
So it's just the reverse of that is the tween, and then all it's doing
所以它的反面是青少年 然后它所做的
is just drawing a rectangle to the screen.
只是在屏幕上画一个矩形
But that's how you get a very simple transition.
但这就是你如何得到一个非常简单的过渡
Same thing for fade to black.
褪色为黑色也是如此
If you want to fade the whole screen to black,
如果您想要将整个屏幕淡出为黑色
just draw a rectangle the size of the screen,
只需画一个屏幕大小的矩形
and then just tween its opacity from 0 to 255, and then vise versa.
然后将其不透明度从0补间到255 反之亦然
That's how you get a simple transition.
这就是你如何得到一个简单的过渡
It can be any color you want.
它可以是你想要的任何颜色
It can be a red transition.
这可能是一个红色过渡
And then the level text, that's just a tween on the y, right?
然后是水平文本 这只是y轴上的一个补间 对吗？
And then I just have some rectangle, love.graphics.rectangle with text,
然后我只有一些矩形 love.graph 带文本的矩形
and it just says timer.tween to like VIRTUAL_HEIGHT divided by 2 minus 8,
它只是写着计时器 像是虚拟高度除以2减去8
and then timer.after1.
然后是定时器 1之后
So we can actually pull this up if we want.
所以如果我们想的话我们可以把它拉上来
We can see how this works.
我们可以看到这是如何运作的
Today's going to be a little wider on the main distro code
今天主要发行版的代码会更宽泛一些
just because a lot of this is more conceptual.
只是因为这其中很多都是概念性的
But in the begin game state-- well, actually, in the start state
但在开始游戏状态下--实际上 在开始状态下
is when we go.
就是我们走的时候
So these colors, and letter table, and stuff that's all for the Match 3 text,
所以这些颜色 字母表 以及所有的东西都是匹配3文本的内容
if you're curious.
如果你好奇的话
So these are all back to what I said earlier about the beginning screen
所有这些都回到了我之前所说的开始屏幕
having Match 3 with the different colors going on a timer.
在计时器上用不同的颜色进行匹配3
These are just tables of colors.
这些只是一些颜色的表格
So notice this is RGBA, and then I'm just performing
请注意 这是RGBA 然后我只是在表演
a shuffle on them every 0.075 seconds.
每隔0.075秒对他们进行一次洗牌
So 2 will get 1, and vise versa.
所以2会得到1 反之亦然
It'll all go down, and then 6 will come up here to 1 every 0.75 seconds.
它会全部下降 然后6每0.75秒就会上升到1
And then M gets mapped to this one, A gets mapped to this one,
然后M映射到这个 A映射到这个
T to this one, C, H, 3, and that's it.
T到这个 C H 3 就是这样
That's done here at line 44 of the start state.
这是在开始状态的第44行完成的
But what I was going to show you was the tween for the transitions.
但我要向你们展示的是过渡的青少年时期
So here in start state, in the update function says,
因此 在这里的开始状态中 在更新函数中
it says if we press Enter, and our current menu item
它说如果我们按Enter 我们当前的菜单项
is 1, meaning that we're on start game, not quit game, timer.tween here.
是1 意味着我们在开始游戏 而不是退出游戏 计时器
And notice that we have a finish function, which will show--
注意 我们有一个Finish函数 它将显示--
I'm actually going to show you in the next couple of examples, the chain
实际上 我将在接下来的几个示例中向您展示 链条
examples.
举个例子
But finish is just a function that you can
但Finish只是一个函数 您可以
run after any timer that just says, hey, when this is finished,
追着任何计时器跑 只要它说 嘿 当这个结束时
run this block of code, and notice that takes anonymous function here,
运行这段代码 注意这里使用匿名函数
just like that.
简单得不得了
So we can say OK, tween, over the course of one second,
所以我们可以说 好的 青少年 在一秒钟的过程中
notice we're passing self into here because we want to manipulate ourself.
请注意 我们将self传递到这里是因为我们想要控制自己
We have a value that we want to manipulate.
我们有一个我们想要操纵的价值
So self.transitionAlpha.
所以就是自己 过渡阿尔法
So we're saying I want to take my transition alpha,
所以我们说我想要我的过渡期阿尔法
and I want it to go to 255, and we set it to 0 by default. So at the very top,
我希望它设置为255 默认情况下我们将其设置为0 所以在最高层
here, at line 60, transition alpha is just our white rectangle that
在这里 在第60行 过渡Alpha就是我们的白色矩形
fills the screen.
填充整个屏幕
I'm just saying set it to 0 so we don't see it at all.
我只是说将它设置为0 这样我们就根本看不到它了
It's going to be invisible.
它将是看不见的
It's still there no matter what.
不管发生什么 它都还在那里
It's hidden, but after we press Enter, tween
它是隐藏的 但在我们按回车键后
it to 255 over the course of 1 second, and then when that's finished,
在1秒内增加到255 然后在完成后
notice this is familiar, right?
注意这是很熟悉的 对吗？
gStateMachine change begin game.
GStateMachine更改开始游戏
We're going to go with the begin game state after that.
在那之后 我们将采用开始游戏状态
Our passing level gets 1.
我们的及格等级是1分
We're starting the game, and then we're going to remove this color.
我们要开始游戏了 然后我们要移除这个颜色
Remove that timer from the-- this is actually
把计时器从--这实际上是
unnecessary in this circumstance, but you can remove timers from timer.
在这种情况下不需要 但您可以从计时器中删除计时器
If you have something going constantly--
如果你有一些事情一直在进行--
in this case, the color timer, and let's say we move from this state
在这种情况下 颜色计时器 假设我们从这个状态
to the next state, the next state doesn't have all those colors,
到下一个状态 下一个状态没有所有这些颜色
right, the Match 3 colors.
对 匹配3种颜色
So we don't need to keep-- because timer is a global object,
所以我们不需要保持--因为计时器是一个全局对象
it's going to keep updating over, and over again.
它将不断更新 一次又一次
We don't need certain timers to exist indefinitely.
我们不需要特定的计时器来无限期地存在
We can just remove this one because it's not relevant anymore.
我们可以删除这个 因为它已经不再相关了
But this is all it takes just to give us a simple transition from one screen
但这就是我们从一个屏幕进行简单转换所需的全部内容
to another.
给另一个人
Just give this transition alpha 255 down in the actual render function.
只需在实际渲染函数中向下提供此过渡Alpha 255即可
Where is it?
它在哪里?
It is right here.
就在这里
So right here.
所以就在这里
Draw our transition rect.
画出我们的过渡矩形
It's going to be drawn last so that it draws over everything when we finally
它将被画在最后 这样当我们最终
do get a transition, but self.transitionAlpha,
确实得到了一个过渡 但它自己 过渡Alpha
and that's all we really need.
这就是我们真正需要的
We need to keep the variable, and then whenever
我们需要保留变量 然后无论何时
we want to perform like some sort of operation over time,
我们想随着时间的推移进行某种手术
just use timer.tween.
只要用定时器就行了
It's that easy.
就这么简单
But that was a little bit of a--
但那是有点--
it was a relevant tangent.
这是一个相关的切线
We would have talked about it anyway, but that's the first use case
无论如何 我们都会讨论它 但这是第一个用例
that I think of in this project, and then also the label.
我在这个项目中想到的 然后还有标签
I'll show you the label in a little bit.
一会儿我会给你看标签的
But I think before we do that, let's talk about chaining.
但我想在此之前 让我们先讨论一下链接
So you guys have probably played a lot of games
所以你们可能玩了很多游戏
where maybe there's a cut scene, and you're looking at a character,
其中可能有一个剪辑场景 而你正在看的是一个角色
and they walk, and then maybe they turn, and they walk in another direction,
他们走着 也许他们转过身 朝另一个方向走去
and they walk up, and then they speak to you.
他们走上前去 然后跟你说话
There's a dialog box, and then maybe they do an animation or something,
有一个对话框 然后他们可能会做一个动画或其他什么
and then maybe some other things happen that are
然后可能会发生一些其他的事情
on some sort of predestined path.
在某种预定的道路上
It's a very discrete path.
这是一条非常离散的道路
It's not random.
这不是随机的
It's laid out in advance.
这是事先安排好的
It's a series of steps, one consecutive.
这是一系列的步骤 一个连续的
That's the concept of chaining things together is relevant
这就是将事物链接在一起的概念是相关的
when we get to sort of timing things because when we finish timing
当我们开始计时时 因为当我们完成计时时
something-- because usually, a lot of those things
一些--因为通常情况下 很多这样的事情
happen over the course of time.
随着时间的推移而发生
Over the course of five seconds, NPC1 will walk up north,
在五秒钟的过程中 NPC1将向北行走
and then they'll turn left, and then they'll say something.
然后他们会向左转 然后他们会说些什么
We want to model that.
我们想以此为榜样
We don't want to basically have variables that say
我们不想基本上有这样的变量
if NPC1 is at this tile, then do this.
如果NPC1在此磁贴上 则执行此操作
If NPC.dialogueOpen, then do this.
如果NPC.DialogueOpen 则执行此操作
We basically want to say walk here, do this, do this,
我们基本上是想说走到这里 做这个 做这个
do this in a flat, easy-- or at least semi-flat, easy sequence of steps.
以平坦、轻松--或者至少是半平坦、简单的顺序--来做这件事
I have a few examples to illustrate how we can do that using timer
我举了几个例子来说明如何使用计时器来实现这一点
for some semi-basic use cases.
用于一些半基本的用例
So chain0 is the first one.
所以chain0是第一个
So this one is just Flappy Bird.
所以这只是Flappy Bird
He's going left to right, then he goes down, then he goes back left again,
他从左到右 然后向下 然后再向左转
and then he goes up.
然后他就上去了
What's the basic way that we model this--
我们建模的基本方式是什么--
that we implement this?
我们要实施这个计划吗？
Just off the cuff.
只是即兴表演
AUDIENCE: We can use that finish thing to do the--
观众：我们可以用这个结束的东西来做--
SPEAKER 1: We would.
演讲者1：我们会
If we didn't know about finish, how would we probably do it?
如果我们不知道Finish 我们会怎么做呢？
I shouldn't have given away finish before I got to that example.
在我讲到那个例子之前 我不应该放弃完成
I kind of got ahead of myself.
我有点超前了
We can imagine somebody maybe saying OK, I
我们可以想象有人可能会说好 我
want Flappy to move left to right, right to bottom, bottom to left,
希望Flappy从左到右 从右到下 从下到左
bottom to up.
从下到上
Maybe they're going to say if Flappy is less than--
也许他们会说如果Flappy不到--
or has reached first point, move left, else if he's reached bottom or point 2,
或者已经到达第一个点 向左移动 否则如果他已经到达底部或第二个点
move down, and then move left, move up.
向下移动 然后向左移动 向上移动
And in both of those cases, they're changing the x and y value of Flappy,
在这两种情况下 它们都改变了Flappy的x和y值
and it's basically just a lot of ifs, and state variables.
这基本上只是一大堆假设和状态变量
I see it in a surprising amount of code.
我在大量的代码中看到了这一点
Just state being kept all over the place.
只是声明到处都是
The first implementation of that that we'll look at uses something similar.
我们将看到的第一个实现使用的是类似的东西
So in chain0, and there's only two examples here, actually, for chain.
所以在chain0中 这里只有两个例子 实际上 关于chain
But chain0, there's a movement time, and then a timer.
但是链0 有一个移动时间 然后是一个计时器
We're going to be semi-clean about it.
我们会对此半清白的
We have some destinations.
我们有一些目的地
OK, so we have destination1.
好的 我们有目的地了
I know that I don't necessarily want to keep track of a bunch of if statements,
我知道我不一定想跟踪一堆if语句
but I'm going for--
但我要去...
assuming that I don't know what timer can do for us,
假设我不知道定时器能为我们做什么
here, I'm just saying OK, I want this first destination
在这里 我只是说好的 我想要这个第一个目的地
to be virtual width minus his width, and then
等于虚拟宽度减去他的宽度 然后
keep him at y0 So right edge of the screen, assuming that he starts at 0,0.
假设他从0 0开始 让他保持在屏幕的右边
And then I want his second destination to be that same side on the x-axis,
然后我希望他的第二个目的地是x轴上的同一侧
but I want the y to be virtual height minus his height.
但我希望y等于他的身高减去他的身高
So go to the bottom of the screen.
因此 请转到屏幕底部
Then I want it to be 0 in his height from the bottom of the screen,
然后我希望从屏幕底部算起他的身高是0
and then back to 0,0.
然后回到0 0
So we have those modeled, and then I want to keep a flag in each of those.
我们制作了这些模型 然后我想在每个模型中都保留一面旗帜
I want to know whether he's reached that state yet.
我想知道他是不是已经到那个地步了
So I'm going to iterate over that table I just created,
所以我将遍历我刚刚创建的表
and just add a new key to each of these called reached,
只需为每个名为REACHED的密钥添加一个新的密钥
and just set it to false.
并将其设置为False
Just by default, he hasn't reached all of them yet.
只是默认的情况下 他还没有联系到所有的人
And then in the update, basically, I'm going
然后在更新中 基本上 我会
to set a timer to the min of movement time.
将计时器设置为移动时间的最小值
So it will never go higher than movement time, and then timer plus delta time.
所以它永远不会超过移动时间 然后是计时器加上增量时间
And then for every destination in destinations, if it wasn't reached,
然后对于目的地中的每个目的地 如果没有到达
then set its x and y, FlappyX and FlappyY, which are, in this case,
然后设置它的x和y、FlappyX和FlappyY 在本例中是
we're uncleanly using global variables to keep track of this.
我们不干净地使用全局变量来跟踪这一点
FlappyX and FlappyY gets baseX.
FlappyX和FlappyY得到Basex
So notice another problem.
因此 请注意另一个问题
We have to maintain where we are relative to our next spot in order
我们必须保持我们相对于下一个位置的位置
for this math to work because before, we just took Flappy Birds--
因为之前我们只用Flappy Birds--
basically, the timer divided by movement time
基本上 计时器除以移动时间
was a ratio where we scaled the end destination,
是我们衡量最终目的地的比率
and assigned that to Flappy, which had the effect of moving
并将其分配给Flappy 它的效果是
Flappy left to right.
Flappy从左到右
But if we do that in the opposite, right to left,
但如果我们用相反的方式 从右到左
the math isn't the same because he's going backwards.
算术不一样 因为他在走回头路
He's getting negative values added to his x value.
他的x值被加上了负值
So we need to keep track of a base that he started at for each
所以我们需要追踪他从哪个基地开始
of these operations baseX, baseY.
在这些行动中 Basex Basey
So at the very beginning, baseX, baseY is 0,0.
所以一开始 Basex Basey是0 0
So it's actually going to be much the same,
所以它实际上会大同小异
but as soon as Flappy get to the right edge of the screen,
但Flappy一到屏幕的右边
we want baseX to be the right edge of the screen, baseY still 0,
我们希望Basex是屏幕的右边缘 Basey仍然是0
and then if he goes down, we want baseY to then be bottom edge of the screen,
如果他倒下了 我们希望贝西成为屏幕的底部边缘
baseX to be right edge, and so forth.
Basex为右边缘 依此类推
So what we do is we just scale.
所以我们要做的就是扩大规模
We're still using a timer over movement time as our scale factor,
我们仍然使用超过移动时间的定时器作为我们的比例因子
but we're adding the difference of our destination and our base,
但我们加上了目的地和基地的差异
and we're multiplying by that scale factor instead.
我们要乘以那个比例因子
And so this difference, if we add it, whether we're
所以这个差异 如果我们加上它 无论我们是
moving left, or right, or down, or up, it's
向左或向右 或向下 或向上 它是
going to have the effect of filling in that gap of bridging that no matter
将起到填补桥梁缺口的作用 无论
where we are, no matter which direction we want to go.
我们在哪里 无论我们想去哪个方向
And so this is basically a fairly complete linear interpolation
所以这基本上是一个相当完整的线性插值法
algorithm, which is the basis of tweening.
算法 这是补间的基础
Just interpolate some value between another value.
只需在另一个值之间插入一些值
It's usually modeled in geometry as the line between two segments.
在几何图形中 它通常被建模为两个线段之间的线
And then if timer gets movement time, we've
如果计时器获得移动时间 我们就
reached our destination, reset the timer, reset or baseX and Y,
到达目的地 重置计时器 重置或Basex和Y
and that has the effect of just doing what we saw earlier, which was just
这样做的效果就像我们之前看到的那样 那就是
putting him point by point.
把他一点一点地放进去
So any questions as to how this interpolation-- how
所以 有没有关于这种插补的问题--如何
this way of modeling the problem works?
这种建模问题的方法有效吗？
All right, so there is a better way, a much better way thanks to timer.finish,
好的 多亏了计时器 还有一种更好的方法 结束
which you can apply to any timer operation, including timer.tween.
您可以将其应用于任何计时器操作 包括timer.tweet
So we can basically say OK, once that operation is finished, do something.
所以我们基本上可以说OK 一旦操作完成 就做点什么
And this is all we have to do, we just have to say timer.tween.
这就是我们要做的 我们只需要说定时器
We no longer have to interpolate at all.
我们不再需要插补
That's taken care of for us by timer.
这是由定时器为我们处理的
So we're doing timer.tween over movement time.
所以我们在做定时器 在移动的时间里
Flappy, set it to-- this was before we add all this in a destinations table
Flappy 将其设置为--这是在我们将所有这些添加到目的地表之前
with reached flags as well.
还带着伸展的旗帜
Now, we just have the x and y here.
现在 我们这里只有x和y
So on the first movement, we want his x to be right edge of the screen,
所以在第一个动作中 我们希望他的x在屏幕的右边
just like before-- y get zero.
就像以前一样--你得零分
Once that's finished, anonymous function with another timer.tween.
完成后 使用另一个定时器的匿名函数 tweet
So we're saying OK, once you're finished,
所以我们说好的 一旦你做完了
then tween him from the top right edge to the bottom right edge.
然后将他从右上边缘补间到右下边缘
So y gets VIRTUAL_HEIGHT minus FlappySprite getHeight.
因此y得到的是VALUAL_HEIGH减去FlappySprite的getHeight
And then once that's finished, another anonymous function,
一旦完成 另一个匿名函数
another timer.tween, another finish, another anonymous function,
另一个计时器 另一个结束 另一个匿名函数
another timer.tween.
另一个定时器
And this is, in its own way, unscalable.
而且 这以其自身的方式是不可扩展的
It's nested.
它是嵌套的
There's a term for it called call back hell
有一个术语叫做召回地狱
because you just get infinite downwards sloping anonymous functions with all
因为你只会得到无限向下倾斜的匿名函数
this behavior.
这种行为
There are ways to flatten it, and we potentially will talk about it.
有一些方法可以让它变得平坦 我们可能会讨论它
It's part of knife.chain.
这是刀的一部分链条
Knife.chain has a way to turn all of these--
Knife.Chain有一种方法来改变所有这些--
basically, it would look something like this.
基本上 它会看起来像这样
It would be chain, and then it would be like moveFlappy x, y.
它将是链状的 然后它将像moveFlappy x y
MoveFlappy x2-- it wouldn't be x2, y2.
MoveFlappy x2--不会是x2 y2
We'd actually write these out here, but it would have the exact same effect.
我们实际上会把这些写在这里 但它会产生完全相同的效果
This is if you're looking to maybe implement a cut scene system, or just
这是如果您想要实现一个场景切换系统 或者只是
some sort of scripting system for your game
为你的游戏设计某种脚本系统
that's very declarative, and imperative in style.
这是非常陈述性的 在风格上也是强制性的
This is the holy grail of changing behavior, and getting it to work,
这是改变行为并使其发挥作用的圣杯
and just making it look nice, and readable.
只是让它看起来很漂亮 而且是可读性的
Yeah?
嗯?
AUDIENCE: Well, you could also pass in--
观众：好的 你也可以进来--
you could pass in a table to your function of x's and y's [INAUDIBLE]
您可以将一个表传递给x和y的函数[INAUDIBLE]
simpler for [INAUDIBLE] to chain a lot of things.
对[INAUDIBLE]来说 链接很多东西更简单
SPEAKER 1: Yes, you could do that too.
演讲者1：是的 你也可以这么做
The response was you could pass in a table to--
回答是 你可以把一个表传递给--
you could iterate over a table, and within that table,
您可以遍历一个表 在该表中
generate a timer.tween.
生成定时器 补间
The only issue comes about with finish, and there is a way--
唯一的问题是Finish 有一种方法--
I guess you could get a reference back to the timer,
我想你可以拿回计时器的参考资料
and then add a finish block to it, but then you would lose out on--
然后给它加一个完工块 但这样你就会失去--
that does work for the same function if all you're doing
如果您所做的所有操作都适用于相同的功能
is moving something to a bunch of locations, it's absolutely true.
把东西搬到很多地方 这绝对是真的
But if we wanted Flappy say something, and hero disappear, and then
但如果我们想让Flappy说点什么 英雄就会消失 然后
hero flash, it gets a little bit trickier to do stuff like that.
英雄闪电侠 做这样的事情会变得有点棘手
But yes, I agree.
但是 是的 我同意
There are ways of modeling-- this particular example is a little bit
建模有多种方法--这个特定的例子有点
repetitive, and could be modeled, I think, better
重复 而且我认为可以更好地模仿
with a function that takes advantage of the fact
具有一个功能 该功能利用
that timers can be returned, and then given new finish variables.
可以返回计时器 然后给出新的Finish变量
I'd have to experiment with it to see because I'm actually not
我得试一试才能明白 因为我实际上不是
100% sure that you can add a finish.
100%确定您可以添加饰面
No, I think you can, actually.
不 我想你可以的 事实上
I think you can add a finish function to a reference
我认为您可以向引用添加Finish函数
because it's just a function on an object.
因为它只是一个对象上的函数
So yeah, but independent of that, I think the goal probably
所以 是的 但除此之外 我认为目标可能是
is one, knowing how we can now chain behavior, and then two,
一个是 知道我们现在可以如何链接行为 然后是第二个
striving towards flattening it.
努力将其夷为平地
But in the purpose of this problem set, we'll see this a couple of times,
但为了这个习题集的目的 我们会看几次
and it's just worlds better than before.
这只是比以前更好的世界
What's this, 76 lines?
这是什么 76行吗？
And then tween1 or chain0 was 96.
然后tween1或chain0等于96
OK, so 20 lines of code.
好的 所以有20行代码
And also the fact that now we have a declarative interface for modeling
还有一个事实是 现在我们有了一个用于建模的声明性接口
asynchronous behavior, that's really the fundamental thing,
异步行为 这确实是最基本的事情
is not having some value that models your duration, or your counter,
不是有某种价值来模拟你的持续时间或你的计数器
or whatever value, but just saying, hey, over this length of time,
或任何价值 但只是说 嘿 在这段时间里
I want you to do this.
我要你做这件事
I want to do this.
我想做这个
After this length of time, I want you to do this.
过了这么长时间 我要你做这件事
I always like to try and strive towards making code as declarative as possible
我总是喜欢尝试并努力使代码尽可能具有声明性
just so that you can read it in the future,
只是为了让你将来能读到它
and then the people working on your code base
然后为您的代码库工作的人员
can also read it well in the future, and I
我以后也能读得很好 我
think timer does a pretty awesome job of that.
我认为Timer在这方面做得相当出色
And this is just a reference for timer finish.
这只是定时器结束的参考
So it just takes a callback, and then once a timer function
所以它只需要一个回调 然后一旦计时器函数
tween every or after has completed, it triggers that callback.
补间间隔或在完成之后 它会触发该回调
So we're going to take a break for five minutes now, and then once we get back,
所以我们现在休息五分钟 然后等我们回来
we'll talk about swapping, and some of the algorithms we use in Match 3,
我们将讨论交换 以及我们在比赛3中使用的一些算法
starting with just rendering a board, getting tiles to swap, tweening them,
从渲染一块木板开始 让瓷砖交换 对它们进行补间
and then we'll actually look at how we take falling tiles,
然后我们将看看我们是如何处理掉下来的瓷砖的
and account for them, and then repopulate them.
并对它们进行解释 然后重新填充它们
All right, we're back.
好了 我们回来了
So recall, before break we were looking at timer,
回想一下 在休息之前 我们看着计时器
and how to take code that was previously managed by timers, and asynchronous,
以及如何获取以前由计时器管理的、异步的代码
but also very stateful, and sort of messy, and all over the place,
但也非常有状态 有点凌乱 到处都是
and putting it into a more declarative, clean,
把它变成一种更具说明性的、干净的、
easy to express format via timer.tween, timer.every, timer.after, timer.finish,
易于通过timer.tweet、timer.each、timer.After、timer.Finish、
timer;finish for any timer objects.
Timer；任何Timer对象都结束
So with all that out of the way, now we'll
所有这些都解决了 现在我们要
start talking about the actual Match 3 mechanics.
开始谈论第三场比赛的实际机制吧
And the very first thing that we'll look at is swap0,
我们首先要看的是swap0
and this is the sprite sheet for Match 3 that's included in the distro.
这是包括在发行版中的《第三场比赛》的精灵版
So as we can see, it's something that we can easily chop up with generate quads,
正如我们所看到的 这是我们可以很容易地用生成四元组来切割的东西
as we saw before.
正如我们之前看到的
Just a function provided in util.lua.
只是util.lua中提供的一个函数
These are all 32 by 32 pixels.
这些都是32x32像素
So it would be very easy just to go through all of them,
因此 只需浏览所有这些内容就很容易了
and basically just generate quads with the sprite sheet 32, 32,
基本上只用精灵薄板32、32生成四边形
and just get a table with all of these individual things.
然后找一张桌子 里面有所有这些单独的东西
But notice that they're blocked up into patterns of colors,
但请注意 它们被遮挡成各种颜色的图案
and this has actual meaning, and value for our game
这对我们的游戏有实际的意义和价值
because when something is the same color,
因为当一些东西是相同的颜色时
and only when something is the same color, a tile is the same color,
只有当东西是相同的颜色时 瓷砖才是相同的颜色
are we allowed to trigger a match with it.
我们可以用它来触发匹配吗
If we get any three or four--
如果我们有三四个--
anything higher than three together in a line, vertically
在垂直方向上 在一条线上超过三个的任何东西
or horizontally, that's a match, and we need to remove it from the table.
或者横向来看 这是一场比赛 我们需要把它从桌子上移走
So we need some sort of way of identifying these tiles as being
所以我们需要某种方式来识别这些瓷砖是
of some color, and then they also happen to have a different pattern on them.
一些颜色 然后它们也碰巧有不同的图案
This one's got nothing, but then an x, and then a circle, and a square.
这个什么都没有 然后是一个x 然后是一个圆 还有一个正方形
So those patterns-- it's not implemented in the distro,
所以那些模式--它没有在发行版中实现
but part of the assignment.
但这是任务的一部分
It's actually going to make them relevant.
这实际上会让它们变得相关
But the part that is implemented is the actual matching of the colors.
但实现的部分是颜色的实际匹配
And so the first thing that we'll need to do, probably, when we actually
所以我们需要做的第一件事 可能是 当我们真正
get into the core code of the distribution
深入了解发行版的核心代码
is instead of just putting them into one table, categorizing them.
不是简单地把它们放在一个表格里 把它们分类
Splitting it up into maybe one, two, three, four, five, six, seven, eight,
把它分成一 二 三 四 五 六 七 八
nine times two--
九乘以二--
18 tables, so that we can just say gframes at color.
18张桌子 这样我们就可以在颜色上说框架了
So color being one to 18, and then get the index into that.
所以颜色是1到18 然后把指数放进去
So there's six within each one.
所以每一个里面都有六个
So it'll be one to six.
所以会是一比六
One to six will be the variety, with one being the base variety.
1至6个为品种 1个为基础品种
And part of the assignment will be make sure
任务的一部分就是确保
that the base variety is the only one that we start with on level one,
基础品种是我们从第一级开始的唯一品种
but then gradually introduce these other varieties.
但随后逐渐引入这些其他品种
And you can put them in whatever hierarchy
你可以把它们放在任何层次结构中
you want to, but make them have some sort of value
你想要 但要让它们有某种价值
later on top of a few other things the assignment will cover.
稍后 作业还将涵盖其他几个方面
But that's the spreadsheet in a nutshell,
但简而言之 这就是电子表格
and we'll be splitting it that way.
我们会以这种方式平分它
So 18 tables of quads, instead of one quad of whatever
所以18张桌子是四份 而不是一张
this amount is-- eight by 16.
这个数字是--8乘16
Not sure how many that is off the top of my head.
不知道有多少是我脑海中浮现的
But let's take a look at swap0 in the distribution
但让我们来看看发行版中的swap0
so we can get a sense of what we need to do
这样我们就能知道我们需要做什么
to begin implementing our Match 3 game.
开始实施我们的第三场比赛
Notice we have require util for GenerateQuads.
请注意 我们已经为GenerateQuad要求了util
We're just going to generate for this basic example.
我们只需要为这个基本的例子生成
We're not going to differentiate between colors, and varieties, or anything.
我们不会区分颜色、品种或任何东西
We're just going to put them all into one quad, or one table of quads.
我们只是要把它们都放进一个四元组 或者一张四元组的桌子
So we're just going to use the regular GenerateQuads function.
因此 我们将只使用常规的GenerateQuads函数
We're not going to differentiate them.
我们不会区分它们
We're just going to use our sprite here, our match3.png
我们将在这里使用我们的精灵 我们的match3.png
provided in the distro, which is the exact same image that we just
在发行版中提供 这与我们刚才的图像完全相同
saw on the screen.
在屏幕上看到的
I'm going to just generate them.
我将只生成它们
They're 32 by 32--
他们是32乘32英寸--
generate the quads for them.
为它们生成四元组
They're 32 by 32 pixels.
它们是32x32像素的
I'm assigning it to a table here called TileQuads.
我将它分配给这里一个名为TileQuads的表
And then here, we're calling generateBoard,
然后在这里 我们调用GenerateBoard
and so generateBoard isn't all that dissimilar to what we saw before
因此 GenerateBoard与我们之前看到的并没有太大的不同
with maybe the level maker in Breakout, where we just spawn a bunch of bricks,
可能是《越狱》中的关卡制造者 我们只是在那里生产了一堆砖
or a bunch of tiles, in this case.
或者一堆瓷砖 在这种情况下
Except in this case, they're kept in a nice 2D array that's
但在这种情况下 它们被保存在一个很好的2D数组中
always going to be eight by eight, and that's never
总是会是8乘8 这永远不会
going to change just by one of the constraints of the game.
仅仅因为这个游戏的其中一个限制而改变
Match 3, traditionally, is an eight by eight grid that's
传统上 第三场比赛是一个8乘8的网格
always full of tiles of some variety.
总是满是各种各样的瓷砖
So local tiles, it's going to be an empty table,
所以当地的瓷砖 它将是一张空桌子
and then we're going to do a nested for loop here--
然后我们将在这里做一个嵌套的for循环--
y to x.
从y到x
The standard is usually y first, and then x,
标准通常是先是y 然后是x
and then we index y before x just because the individual rows in a 2D
然后我们在x之前对y进行索引 因为2D中的各个行
array, or sprite, or table will be such that, for example, if our table was
数组、子画面或表将是这样的 例如 如果我们的表
equal to this-- oops, sorry.
等于这个--哦 对不起
Syntax bug.
语法错误
If we did this, and then we have a table here, and a table here, and a table
如果我们这样做 然后我们有一张桌子 一张桌子
here, and we had like 0, 1, 1, 1, 1, 1, 1, 1, and then 1, 1, 1, 1.
这里 我们有0 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 然后是1 1 1 1
If we index into this table--
如果我们索引这张表--
so table at 0, that's going to give us another table.
所以桌子在0 这会给我们带来另一张桌子
That's not going to give us--
这不会给我们带来--
let's say we wanted to get the value at table 2, 3.
假设我们想要得到表2 3中的值
The instinct might be to think I'm going to index at x, y
我的直觉可能是认为我将在x y处建立索引
just because x, y tends to be more commonly seen.
只是因为x y往往更常见
But if we did that, and assumed that x was horizontal,
但如果我们这样做 并假设x是水平的
and y is vertical in this arrangement, which is how we have it,
而y在这个排列中是垂直的 这就是我们的方式
then table2 wouldn't be this value here table2 would be this table here.
那么表2就不是这个值了 表2就是这个表了
The first value you passed into indexing some table when it's a nested table
当某个表是嵌套表时 您传递到索引该表的第一个值
is just, in fact, the table itself, which
实际上 就是表本身 它
is why we actually need to do-- when we want to get some value,
这就是为什么我们实际上需要做的--当我们想要获得一些价值时
we have to index at table y, x.
我们必须在表y x处建立索引
So it's flipped for that reason because x is actually going to be--
因此它被翻转了 因为x实际上将是--
the first index is going to be these sub tables,
第一个索引将是这些子表
or sub arrays if you're in C, or Java, or something like that.
或者子数组 如果你用的是C 或者Java 或者类似的语言
So when you see table y, x, and you're wondering why it's not table x,
所以当你看到表y x时 你会奇怪为什么它不是表x
y, that's the reason.
Y 这就是原因
So any questions as to why that is, or how that works?
那么 对于为什么会这样 或者这是如何运作的 有什么问题吗？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不见]
SPEAKER 1: In this case, I was using zero based indexing,
演讲者1：在这种情况下 我使用了从零开始的索引
but Lua is one index.
但Lua是一个指数
That was just habit.
那只是习惯而已
It was pointed out that I was using zero based indexing in my example.
有人指出 我在我的示例中使用了从零开始的索引
You want to use one based indexing when you're actually programming,
当您实际编程时 您希望使用一个基于索引的索引
and not zero based.
而不是从零开始
But the same principle applies.
但同样的原则也适用于此
Zero would be one in that case.
在这种情况下 零将是一
In a general purpose language--
用一种通用语言--
most languages, if we were to abstract the problem out in a C 2D array,
大多数语言 如果我们将问题抽象为C2D数组
or C++, or Java, zero would be appropriate there.
或者C++ 或者Java 零在那里是合适的
But anyways, we have a nested for loop.
但无论如何 我们有一个嵌套的for循环
We're starting at y, and then we're going to x,
我们从y开始 然后我们再到x
and then basically, that has the effect of y,
然后基本上 这就是y的效果
and then x, x, x, x, x, y, x, x, x, x, x.
然后是x y x x
Just insert a blank table.
只需插入一个空白表格
Fill it with-- we're just using tables here.
把它填满--我们只是在用桌子
So we're not using any sort of tile class,
所以我们没有使用任何类型的瓷砖类
or board class, or anything fancy.
或者上冲浪板课 或者任何花哨的东西
We're just using raw data types here.
我们在这里只使用原始数据类型
So we're just saying insert into tiles y, which
所以我们只是说插入到瓷砖y中 这
by the way, if we're at x equals 1, 8, here,
顺便说一句 如果我们在这里x等于1 8
and we're in any given iteration of our outer y loop,
我们处于外部y循环的任意给定迭代中
tiles y will be the last table that we just inserted--
瓷砖y将是我们刚刚插入的最后一张表--
the last blank table on the first iteration of this x loop.
此x循环的第一次迭代上的最后一个空白表
So basically, it's saying, in the inner table that I just
所以基本上 它是说 在内表中 我只是
put into the table that's going to represent our board, the tiles table,
放进代表我们的棋盘的桌子里 瓷砖桌子
insert a new table.
插入新表格
So we have a table of tables of tables.
所以我们有一张桌子 一张桌子 一张桌子
In the third table are the actual tiles themselves.
第三个表中是实际的瓷砖本身
You can think of this table as being a tile data type, more or less.
您可以认为这个表或多或少是一种平铺数据类型
Just implemented using a table.
只是使用表实现的
That has an x-coordinate, a y-coordinate, and then a tile,
它有一个x坐标 一个y坐标 然后是一个瓷砖
and the tile is going to be a random number that's
瓷砖将是一个随机数字
going to be the index into our quads.
将成为我们四人组的索引
So each tile holds x and y, and then notice
所以每个瓷砖都有x和y 然后请注意
that we're multiplying by 32 because we're
我们乘以32是因为我们
going to use this to draw the tile, and the tiles are 32 pixels tall by high--
我要用这个来画瓷砖 瓷砖是32像素高的--
sorry, wide by tall.
抱歉 太高了
We are going to multiply x minus 1, recall,
我们要乘以x减1 回想一下
because even though tables are one indexed, coordinates are zero indexed.
因为即使表是一个索引的 坐标也是零索引的
So x gets that times 32, y gets that times 32,
所以x乘以32 y乘以32
and then get a random number between 1, and the number of quads
然后得到一个介于1和四元组数量之间的随机数
in our tile quads table.
在我们的四边形瓷砖桌子上
So recall this number sign here is just a shorthand for length of the table,
回想一下 这里的数字符号只是桌子长度的速记
and then we're going to return it.
然后我们会把它还回去
So we generated our board.
因此 我们产生了我们的董事会
It's a y by x grid of table rows of little tables
它是一个y x x网格 由小桌子组成的表格行
that all have an x, y, and a tile ID, and the tile ID maps to the quads
都具有x、y和切片ID 并且切片ID映射到四元组
that we just generated.
我们刚刚生成的
OK, that's it for the init function.
好了 init函数就是这样了
Sorry, love.load in this example.
在本例中 对不起是love.Load
The love.draw uses a function called drawBoard, and we pass in 128 by 16.
Drave使用一个名为DrawBoard的函数 我们传入128乘以16
The 128 by 16 is just xy offsets.
128乘以16只是xy偏移量
We're just going to draw our board at 128, 16,
我们要在128 16点抽签
and is it going to center our board.
它会成为我们董事会的中心吗
And then if we go down to drawBoard at line 89,
如果我们往下走到第89行的DrawBoard
gets an offsetX, offsetY, nested for loop again.
获取再次嵌套的for循环的offsetX、offsetY
We're just iterating back over the tiles that we got,
我们只是在重复我们得到的瓷砖
and recall, actually, generateBoard returns tiles,
回想一下 实际上 GenerateBoard返回的是瓷砖
and then we set board equal to the result of generateBoard.
然后我们将Board设置为等于GenerateBoard的结果
So down here in line 89, again, in drawBoard-- actually at line 95.
所以在这里的第89行 也是在DrawBoard中--实际上在第95行
Within this nested for loop, we're going to get a tile at board y, x,
在这个嵌套的for循环中 我们将在板y x
just so we have a shorthand reference for it.
只是为了让我们有一个速记参考
We don't have to say board y, x several times, which you would have to hear.
我们不需要多次说黑板y x 这是你必须听到的
We're going to draw the sprite--
我们要画出精灵--
the quad at tile, tile, tile.tile, which, recall,
瓦片 回想一下
is a random number between one and whatever
是一个介于1和任何值之间的随机数
the number of quads we have in our tile quads table.
我们的瓷砖四元组表格中有四元组的数量
And then that x plus offsetX, and the y plus the offsetY, which
然后x加上偏移量X y加上偏移量Y 这
has the effect of drawing every single tile in our grid at some given offset.
可以在给定的偏移量上绘制网格中的每一块瓷砖
And that has the result--
这就产生了结果--
and I probably should have run this, actually, in advance
实际上 我可能应该提前运行这段视频
just so I could illustrate it.
这样我就可以举例说明了
But we have a simple board.
但我们有一块简单的冲浪板
Looks nice.
看起来不错
It's colorful, but it's very, very basic.
它是五颜六色的 但它非常 非常基本
Just a 2D render of our game.
只是我们游戏的2D渲染
There's no behavior or anything.
没有任何行为或任何东西
This is just how we draw the board.
这只是我们画棋盘的方式
So any questions as to how just the drawing, and the creation of the board
所以 有没有什么问题 比如图纸和黑板的制作
work?
工作?
OK.
好的
So swap1 is a little bit more complicated.
因此 swap1稍微复杂一些
It builds on what we did before, what we just
它建立在我们以前所做的基础上 我们只是
built, which was getting the board implemented, and drawn onto the screen.
建立 这是实现董事会 并绘制到屏幕上
But there's no behavior at all.
但它们根本没有任何行为
It's just a static-- basically, the same thing
这只是一个静电--基本上是一样的东西
as drawing an image onto the screen.
将图像绘制到屏幕上
And so for that, what we want to do is implement swapping.
因此 我们想要做的是实现交换
So how do we think we can accomplish this?
那么 我们认为如何才能做到这一点呢？
Anybody have any ideas as to how we can swap?
有没有人有办法让我们互换？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE] using tweening to have it go in opposite directions.
观众：(听不见)用补丁让它朝相反的方向移动
SPEAKER 1: Well, we could.
演讲者1：嗯 我们可以
That will have the effect of--
这将会产生--
the response was we could use tweeting.
得到的回应是我们可以使用推特
We could, and we actually will for swap2,
我们可以 实际上我们也会这样做
but it's going to be a little bit more complicated than that
但事情会比这更复杂一点
because they're in a 2D array.
因为它们是在2D阵列中
So if we just tween their x, y--
所以如果我们只是在他们的x之间 你--
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不见]
SPEAKER 1: They will be in the same place in the array.
演讲者1：它们将在阵列中的相同位置
But yes, ultimate--
但是 是的 终极--
AUDIENCE: You could switch the position in the array,
观众：你可以在阵列中交换位置
and then reload the array.
然后重新加载阵列
SPEAKER 1: Switch their position in the array, and then reload the array.
扬声器1：交换它们在阵列中的位置 然后重新加载阵列
We will switch the position.
我们将调换位置
We don't have to reload the array, but we will switch their positions.
我们不需要重新加载阵列 但我们会改变它们的位置
That's effectively, what it is.
这是有效的 它是什么
Literally just take two tiles, and swap in CS50,
从字面上看 只需取两块瓷砖 并交换到CS50
where we just take two variables, and get a temp variable that
我们只需要取两个变量 然后得到一个临时变量
points that one variable, gets its values
指向一个变量 获取它的值
while the second variable gets the values of that one, or vise versa,
而第二个变量获取该变量的值 反之亦然
I think.
我认为
This one gets this one's values, this one gets this one's values,
这个得到这个的值 这个得到这个的值
and then this one comes down to this one, basically.
然后这个基本上归结到这个
There's the middleman that keep-- because if this one gets this one's
有一个中间人一直在--因为如果这个人得到这个人
values, it's going to get overridden by this one's value.
值 它将被这个值覆盖
So there would be no reference to it's x, y, or anything.
所以不会有关于它的x y 或任何东西的引用
So that's why you need to store this one up here, so this one can come here,
这就是为什么你需要把这个放在这里 这样这个就可以放在这里
and this and come back down here.
然后再回到这里来
So we've done a swap, effectively.
因此 我们已经进行了有效的互换
And there's ways in Lua to do swaps, as we saw before,
正如我们之前看到的 在Lua有办法进行掉期交易
without even needing a temporary variable.
甚至不需要临时变量
You can just do xy get some other xy, which sort of bypasses that.
你可以做一些其他的XY 这样可以绕过这一点
But when you start to do four things getting swapped at once,
但当你开始一次做四件事被交换时
and you have four commas, it can get a little tricky, a little bit unwieldy.
而且你有四个逗号 它可能会变得有点棘手 有点笨拙
I'm actually not 100% sure you can unpack more than two things in Lua.
事实上 我不能百分百确定你可以在Lua打开两个以上的东西
I'll have to double check on that, but right off the gate,
我得再查一遍 但马上就要到了
we're seeing that double assignment here on line 32,
我们在第32行看到了双重任务
highlighted x, highlighted y gets 1, 1.
高亮显示x 高亮显示y得到1 1
And let me actually run just so we can see.
让我实际运行 这样我们就可以看到了
There's actually a couple of pieces here besides just that.
实际上 除了这些 这里还有几件
Swap1.
交换1
So we have the board as before, we also have
所以我们和以前一样有董事会 我们也有
something to show us where to swipe because we have
一些东西可以告诉我们在哪里刷 因为我们有
to know where we're swapping the tiles.
知道我们在哪里交换瓷砖
In an ideal implementation, which is an optional part of the assignment,
在作为分配的可选部分的理想实现中
you would have mouse behavior for your game.
你的游戏会有鼠标行为
So you could just click on two tiles, or click, and drag, and swap them.
因此 您只需单击两个磁贴 或者单击、拖动并交换它们
In this case, we're not doing that.
在这种情况下 我们不会这么做
We're just implementing key based behavior.
我们只是实现了基于键的行为
So when I press left, right, up, or down, I can move.
所以当我按向左、向右、向上或向下时 我可以移动
If I press Enter on a tile, and then move around, it's an indicator to me
如果我在磁贴上按Enter键 然后四处移动 这对我来说是一个指示器
that I've selected that tile to swap with something else
我已经选择了那块瓷砖与其他东西互换
because it needs to keep track of OK, you want to swap this tile.
因为它需要跟踪OK 所以您想要交换此磁贴
What do you want to swap it with?
您想用什么来交换呢？
I want to swap it with this tile.
我想把它换成这块瓷砖
So they get swapped.
所以他们被交换了
Or this tile.
或者这块瓷砖
So you can swap it with whatever tile you want to.
所以你可以把它换成你想要的任何瓷砖
There's no constraints.
没有任何限制
The actual distro code implements a constraint, and so offhand,
实际的发行版代码实现了一个约束 因此
what do you think a constraint would be for making sure that we can't--
你认为什么样的约束才能确保我们不能--
AUDIENCE: They have to be adjacent.
观众：它们必须是相邻的
SPEAKER 1: Yeah, they have to be adjacent.
演讲者1：是的 它们必须是相邻的
So what would that entail?
那么 这将需要什么呢？
AUDIENCE: That their x [INAUDIBLE]
观众：他们的x[INAUDIBLE]
SPEAKER 1: Exactly.
演讲者1：完全正确
And the shorthand for that, really, is if the absolute value of their x's
简而言之 如果他们的x的绝对值
minus their y's is equal to 1.
减去他们的y等于1
Because if you subtract one's x from another one's x,
因为如果你用一个人的x减去另一个人的x
and then one's y from another one's y, and then
然后一个是y 另一个是y 然后
you add the differences together, that'll
你把这些差异加在一起 那就是
tell you whether they're directly adjacent to each other.
告诉你它们是否直接相邻
It has to equal one.
它必须等于1
If equals zero, then their x's and y's are the same.
如果等于零 那么它们的x和y是相同的
If equals two, then it's two tiles away on the x-axis,
如果等于2 那么它在x轴上是两块瓷砖
or it's away on the x and the y, in which case it would be diagonal to it.
或者它在x和y上 在这种情况下 它与它是对角的
So the only way is it's x's minus it's x's.
所以唯一的方法是x减去x的
Tile1.x minus tile2.x, and tile1.y minus tile2.y,
Tile1.x减去tile2.x tile1.y减去tile2.y
if they're absolute value of their difference is one,
如果它们的绝对值之差为1
then they're adjacent.
那么它们是相邻的
That's in the implementation.
这是在实现中
So this is why we have these variables here, highlighted tile.
这就是为什么我们在这里有这些变量 突出显示的瓷砖
Basically we're setting a flag saying, do we have a highlighted tile?
基本上 我们是在设置一面旗帜 上面写着 我们有突出显示的磁贴吗？
If we do, we're going to perform some drawing logic later down in the draw
如果我们这样做了 我们将在稍后的绘图中执行一些绘图逻辑
function.
功能
Basically, how would we draw a highlighted tile, do you think?
基本上 我们将如何绘制突出显示的瓷砖 你认为呢？
AUDIENCE: Add a rectangle with transparency.
观众：添加一个透明的矩形
SPEAKER 1: Exactly.
演讲者1：完全正确
So the answer was add a rectangle with transparency.
所以答案是添加一个透明的矩形
That's exactly what we do.
这正是我们要做的
I'm going to go down to this part here.
我将在这里深入到这部分
So on line 173, if we have a highlighted tile,
所以在第173行 如果我们有一个突出显示的磁贴
and basically, this is in the middle of a loop--
基本上 这是在一个循环的中间--
our y, x before.
我们之前的y x
We've put it into a draw board.
我们已经把它放到了绘图板上
We have the drawBoard function, but x, y, or y, x,
我们有DrawBoard函数 但是x y 或者y x
the tile is going to be whatever tile we're currently on,
瓷砖将是我们目前所在的瓷砖
and if we do have a highlighted tile, and that tile's gridX--
如果我们有一个突出显示的瓷砖 而且那个瓷砖是GRIDX--
notice we now have a new variable called gridX, as opposed to it's regular x
请注意 我们现在有一个名为gridX的新变量 而不是常规的x
so that we can check for these sorts of things to see where it is in the array.
这样我们就可以检查这些东西 看看它在数组中的什么位置
If it's gridX is equal to whatever we've set highlightedX to,
如果GRIDX等于我们设置的高亮X
and gridY is equal to highlightedY, then love.graphics.setColor
GRIDY等于高亮Y 然后是love.graph ics.setColor
half transparency, and then just draw a rectangle with this 4
半透明 然后用这个4画一个矩形
at the end of it, which actually draws a rounded rectangle.
在它的末尾 它实际上绘制了一个圆角矩形
If you pass in no 4, it will just draw straight rectangle,
如果你传4号 它只画直的矩形
but if you pass in an int at the very end, that's how many
但是如果在最后传入一个int 那么就是这个数字
rounded segments basically that rectangle will have.
圆角的线段基本上就是那个矩形
So you can get rounded corners on your rectangles,
所以你可以在你的矩形上得到圆角
and it's good for UI drawing, and stuff like that.
而且它对用户界面绘制和诸如此类的东西都很好
We use it a little bit in the distro.
我们在发行版中稍微用到了它
So that's how you get a highlighted tile.
这就是你如何得到一个突出显示的瓷砖
There was also a selected tile, and a selected tile
还有一个选定的切片和一个选定的切片
is just draw a rectangle, same thing, but it's a line this time,
就是画一个矩形 一样的东西 但这次是一条线
and there's always going to be a selected tile no matter what.
无论如何 总会有一个选定的磁贴
So we're always going to draw it here at the end of our render function.
所以我们总是在渲染函数的末尾绘制它
It's just 255--
只有255--
234 for the opacity so that it's just kind of transparent, but not super
234对于不透明 所以它只是一种透明 但不是超级的
transparent.
透明的
Set line width to 4 so that it's not just a very thin rectangle.
将线宽设置为4 这样它就不会只是一个非常细的矩形
If you set the line width, and then you draw a rectangle with the line format--
如果你设置了线宽 然后用线条格式画了一个矩形--
the line mode of drawing, it will use whatever the current line
绘制的线条模式 它将使用任何当前线条
width is when drawing the rectangle.
宽度是绘制矩形时的宽度
So we set it to 4, then draw a line rect at selectedTile.x
因此 我们将其设置为4 然后在seltedTile.x处绘制一条RECT线
plus offsetX selectedTile.y offsetY, and we draw it 32 by 32
加上OffsetX选定的Tile.Y OffsetY 我们将其绘制为32乘以32
because that's the size of a tile, and then
因为那是瓷砖的大小 然后
we set our color-- remember to always set your color back to 255, 255, 255,
我们设置了颜色--记住始终将颜色设置回255、255、255
255 because if you don't, and I did this when I was debugging, actually,
255因为如果你不这样做 事实上 我在调试的时候做了这个
you get some fun stuff.
你会得到一些有趣的东西
Wait, was that the right one?
等等 是不是就是这个？
Oh, I might have fixed it up above where we--
哦 我可能已经把它修好了--
there was an issue.
这是一个问题
If you don't set, basically, your color, and you set it to red,
如果你不设置 基本上是你的颜色 你把它设置成红色
everything will draw red after you've done something.
在你做了一些事情之后 一切都会变红的
So if it ever happens, remember to set your color back to 255, 255, 255, 255,
因此 如果发生这种情况 请记住将颜色设置回255、255、255、255
anytime you change the color in some way, like I'm doing here.
任何时候你以某种方式改变颜色 就像我在这里做的那样
AUDIENCE: Alternatively, you could also just
观众：或者 你也可以
make sure to always set the color before you draw something. is that right?
在你画东西之前 一定要先设定好颜色 是那么回事吗？
SPEAKER 1: Yes.
演讲者1：是的
The response was make sure you always set
回答是确保您始终设置
the color before you draw something.
在你画东西之前的颜色
I think that's what I ended up doing in this distro, which
我想这就是我最终在这个发行版中做的事情 它
is why it's not working anymore.
这就是为什么它不再起作用了
I think it was--
我想那是...
where was it?
它在哪里？
It was here, but I must have fixed it because I accidentally
它在这里 但我一定是修好了 因为我不小心
left that out when I was debugging, and it ended up drawing-- everything
我在调试的时候把它漏掉了 结果画出了--所有的东西
was red.
是红色的
So just as an aside just because Love2D is a state machine.
因此 顺便说一句 Love2D是一个状态机
Drawing it beforehand is definitely the safer way to go too.
事先把它画出来肯定也是更安全的方式
So the core of this, because we're running a little low on time--
所以这件事的核心 因为我们的时间不多了--
the core of this overall block of code is just the swap here.
整个代码块的核心就是这里的交换
So if there is no highlighted tile-- so basically,
因此 如果没有突出显示的磁贴--所以基本上
if we pressed Enter or Return--
如果我们按Enter或Return--
now, we have all input handling in love.keypressed key.
现在 我们在love.key按键中完成了所有的输入处理
And by the way, this is input handling to change
顺便说一句 这是要更改的输入处理
the x and y of our selected tile.
所选瓷砖的x和y
If we press Enter, and we don't have a highlighted tile,
如果我们按Enter键 并且没有突出显示的磁贴
then we need to have a highlighted tile, otherwise we should swap them.
然后我们需要有一个突出显示的瓷砖 否则我们应该交换它们
So we get a reference to tile one and two, we swap, we create temp variables.
所以我们得到了第一块和第二块的引用 我们交换 我们创建临时变量
Recall, we need to have that middle man up here that
回想一下 我们需要让中间人站在这里
keeps track of this tile's information.
跟踪此磁贴的信息
So it's going to keep track of all of tile2's information
所以它将跟踪所有标题2的S信息
with tempX, tempY, tempgridX, and tempgridY because we
使用tempX、tempy、tempgridX和tempgridY 因为我们
need to not only change their x-coordinates,
不仅需要改变它们的x坐标
but also their grid positions.
还有他们的网格位置
And then we need to create a temp tile here.
然后我们需要在这里创建一个临时瓷砖
Basically, here's where we actually swap their places in the board.
基本上 这就是我们实际上交换他们在董事会中的位置的地方
So tile1.gridY, tile1.gridX gets tile2, and then we're getting a reference
所以标题为1.gridY 标题为1.gridX 标题为2 然后我们得到一个引用
to temp tile so that we can--
让瓷砖临时工 这样我们就可以--
because if we set board at wherever tile1 is to tile2,
因为如果我们把木板放在瓷砖1到瓷砖2的任何地方
we won't have anything where tile2 is.
我们不会有任何东西在Tle2的地方
We need to have a temp tile to keep track of--
我们需要一个临时瓷砖来跟踪--
sorry, we won't have anything at tile1 if we overwrite it with tile2.
对不起 如果我们用磁贴2覆盖它 我们将不会有磁贴1的任何东西
So we need a reference to tile1 here, so that we can put it
所以我们需要在这里引用tile1 这样我们就可以把它
into where tile2's spot is, right here.
进入2‘S点在哪里 就在这里
And then we need to do all that before we end up swapping their coordinates
然后我们需要在我们最终交换他们的坐标之前完成所有这些
and tile grid positions, otherwise you get weird buggy behavior
和平铺网格位置 否则会出现奇怪的错误行为
when you're moving the selected tile around.
当您移动选定的瓷砖时
And then we can on the highlight, and then reset our selection
然后我们可以突出显示 然后重置选择
because their selection is also going to get changed after we do the swap.
因为他们的选择也会在我们交换之后发生变化
So we need to put it to the second tile because it gets swapped with whatever
所以我们需要把它放到第二个瓷砖上 因为它可以与任何东西交换
tile we highlighted.
我们突出显示的磁贴
And that's the overall gist.
这就是总体要旨
It's basically taking two tiles, flipping the information,
它基本上是拿两块瓷砖 翻转信息
storing a middleman.
储存一个中间人
Same thing in swap in CS50, a little more complicated,
CS50中的掉期也是如此 稍微复杂一些
though because these all have subfields that all need to get manipulated.
不过 因为这些都有需要处理的子字段
And a lot of this can actually be done mathematically.
实际上 其中很多都可以通过数学运算来实现
You can actually have its x and y mathematically derived
你实际上可以用数学方法推导出它的x和y
from it's gridX and gridY.
来自GridX和Gridy
Just multiply by 32.
只需乘以32即可
In this case, I just kept them as variables, and separate.
在这种情况下 我只是将它们作为变量 并将其分开
But yeah, you could just do that too, and that
但是 是的 你也可以这样做 而且
has the effect of swapping the variables whenever we move them,
只要我们移动变量 就会产生交换变量的效果
and then that's the fundamental first step in Match 3,
这是第三场比赛最基本的第一步
is just swapping any two tiles in a given position.
只是在给定位置交换任意两个瓷砖
So does that make sense altogether?
那么 这完全说得通吗？
OK.
好的
So this example is actually not that much different at all from swap2.
因此 这个示例实际上与Swap2没有太大不同
I'm going to show you swap 2 right now.
现在 我将向你们展示交换2
So if we go to swap2, the only change we really have made
因此 如果我们转到Swap2 我们真正做的唯一更改
is that now tiles flipped instead of instantly changing, they tween.
现在瓷砖翻转 而不是立即改变 他们之间
And this is a piece of cake at this point.
在这一点上 这是小菜一碟
We already know-- what's the function we need to do?
我们已经知道--我们需要做什么功能？
Just timer.tween.
只是计时器而已
All we need to do is just take the two, and then just
我们所要做的就是带走这两个人 然后
tween tile1.x and tile1.y to tile2.x, and tile2.y,
从tile1.x和tile1.y到tile2.x和tile2.y
and do the same thing in reverse.
然后反向做同样的事情
Tween tile2.x, and tile2.y to tile1.x, and tile1.y.
从tile2.x和tile2.y到tile1.x和tile1.y
And so if we open up swap2, go to main, nothing in this program
所以如果我们打开Swap2 转到Main 在这个程序中什么都没有
really changes, except in update, where we go to line 99,
真正的变化 除了在更新中 我们转到第99行
and we're just doing it here.
而我们只是在这里做这件事
Notice the definition.
请注意其定义
Over 0.2 seconds, it takes in the definition table, here,
在0.2秒内 它在定义表中 这里
and it's taking in two entities because we're modifying two things.
它接受了两个实体 因为我们正在修改两个东西
We're modifying tile2, and tile1.
我们正在修改标题2和标题1
We're just setting x to tile1.x, and y to tile1.y,
我们只是将x设置为tile1.x y设置为tile1.y
and then tile1 is getting the tempX and tempY
然后Tle1得到了tempX和Tempy
because before, it was just getting it directly from the temp,
因为以前 它只是直接从临时工那里拿到的
and now it's just tweening it over time.
现在 它只是随着时间的推移而调整
But that was before just a bunch of tile2.x equals tile1.x,
但那是在一堆tile2.x等于tile1.x之前
tile2.y equals tile2.y, tile1.y equals tile2.y.
Tile2.y等于tile2.y tile1.y等于tile2.y
That's all it is.
仅此而已
That's what's really nice about it.
这就是它真正好的地方
Now we don't have to really work hard at all
现在我们根本不需要真正努力工作
to get nice, smooth transitions in whatever we do,
为了在我们所做的任何事情中获得良好、平稳的过渡
whether it's a UI, or the game.
无论是用户界面 还是游戏
It's just super nice, and convenient.
它太棒了 而且很方便
So that's all we need to do to get basic swapping done.
因此 我们需要做的就是完成基本的掉期交易
That was swap2, the tween swap.
那是Swap2 青少年互换
And so I put together a set of slides here just
所以我在这里放了一组幻灯片
to illustrate the algorithm that we use to calculate the matches.
来说明我们用来计算匹配的算法
So right now we've got swapping in, but we
所以现在我们可以换货 但我们
don't know when we've gotten a match.
不知道我们什么时候找到匹配的了
So just offhand, does anybody have any idea as to maybe
所以 顺便说一句 有没有人知道
how we can go about calculating whether we've got any matches?
我们怎样才能开始计算我们是否有匹配的呢？
AUDIENCE: Well, we already figured out how to track if a thing is adjacent.
观众：嗯 我们已经知道了如何追踪一个物体是否相邻
So you, I guess, have a table of adjacent--
所以 我想 你有一张相邻的桌子--
you go through [INAUDIBLE] block, and if you have an adjacent--
你穿过[INAUDIBLE]区块 如果你有一个相邻的--
or for every adjacent block, you check if that color equals your color.
或者 对于每个相邻的块 检查该颜色是否与您的颜色相同
And if it does, you check if--
如果是这样的话 你会检查是否--
well, then I guess you need to figure out what direction it's in,
好吧 那我想你需要弄清楚它在哪个方向
and then you check, continuing in that direction,
然后你检查 继续往那个方向走
if there's another of the same color.
如果有另一个同样颜色的
SPEAKER 1: So their response was when you're
演讲者1：所以他们的反应是当你
looking at tiles, look at all adjacent tiles,
看看瓷砖 看看所有相邻的瓷砖
and if there is a color that's the same one, then figure out its direction,
如果有一种颜色是相同的 那么就找出它的方向
and then move from there.
然后从那里搬出去
So like a recursive style.
就像一种递归风格
I guess you could implement it recursively.
我想您可以递归地实现它
It probably would be a little bit trickier to understand, and probably
它可能会更难理解 而且可能
not as efficient.
效率不是很高
The way that we are actually going to implement it
我们实际上要实施它的方式
is going to be a little bit more iterative.
将会有更多的迭代
So all we really need to do is check every row, and every column one time,
所以我们真正需要做的就是检查每一行 每一列
and then go basically, left to right.
然后基本上 从左到右
So in this case, we have to check every row and column one
所以在这种情况下 我们必须检查每一行和每一列
time in this direction, and then one time in this direction
朝这个方向走一次 然后朝这个方向走一次
because we can get vertical and horizontal matches.
因为我们可以得到垂直和水平匹配
So we start off.
所以我们开始吧
Let's just arbitrarily decide we want to start going left to right down the data
让我们随意决定我们要开始从左到右查看数据
structure.
结构
So we'll go, what color is this?
那我们就去 这是什么颜色的？
That's brown.
那是棕色的
OK, check the next one.
好的 检查下一个
Is it the same color?
是同样的颜色吗？
If it is, then say OK, the number of matching tiles that we've found so far
如果是 则说确定 即我们到目前为止找到的匹配切片的数量
is two.
是两个
If it's greater than three, then later on we'll
如果它大于3 那么稍后我们将
need to add that group as a match to our list of matches, basically.
基本上 需要将该组作为匹配添加到我们的匹配列表中
But if it's not, OK, then the number matches is one again.
但如果不是 那么匹配的数字又是1
So set it to one, and then do the same thing.
因此 将其设置为1 然后执行相同的操作
Same color?
一样的颜色？
No.
不是的
OK, number of matches is one.
好的 匹配的次数是1
In this case, here we have the number of matches is going to be two
在这种情况下 匹配的数量将是两个
because this is blue, and then we're going to go ahead,
因为这是蓝色的 然后我们要继续
and then same color again.
然后又是同样的颜色
The number matches is three, and then we've gotten to the end of the row.
匹配的数字是三个 然后我们就到了这一排的最后
So we can say OK, what was our last number of matches?
所以我们可以说 我们最后一次比赛的次数是多少？
Was it greater than or equal to three?
它是大于还是等于三？
If it was, add that group of tiles to our table of
如果是 请将该组瓷砖添加到我们的
matches if we've gotten a match, and then move on.
如果我们找到匹配的话 然后继续前进
And we do that over, and over again, and if it's in the middle of a group,
我们一遍又一遍地做这件事 如果它是在一个小组的中间
like it is here-- so this isn't at the end of the row.
就像它在这里一样--所以这不是排在最后的
This is just in the middle of the row.
这就在这一排的中间
What we do is number of matches one, two, three, and then we go here,
我们要做的是一、二、三场比赛 然后我们来到这里
and it's set to one.
而且它被设置为1
Well, first of all, we check number of matches
好的 首先 我们检查匹配的数量
when we get to a different color.
当我们看到不同的颜色时
We say, OK, this isn't the same color as this tile.
我们说 好的 这和这块瓷砖的颜色不一样
This is purple, and this is gray, but number of matches is three.
这个是紫色的 这个是灰色的 但匹配的数量是三个
So what we do is we just add these three tiles to our--
所以我们要做的就是把这三块瓷砖加到我们的--
we're keeping a table of matches because we're going to go through,
我们准备了一桌火柴 因为我们要通过
and we're going to delete all of them.
我们要把它们全部删除
And then, eventually, we're going to do some tweening as well,
然后 最终 我们还会做一些补丁
but we're going to delete all of these.
但我们将删除所有这些内容
And then in order to do that, we need to walk backwards.
然后为了做到这一点 我们需要向后走
We need to say, basically, for x gets position
我们需要说 基本上 因为x得到了位置
minus number of tiles in the match, just add that to a match,
减去匹配中的瓷砖数量 只需将其添加到匹配中
add that to a match,
把它加到火柴上 再加到火柴上
and then add the match to our table of matches.
然后将火柴添加到我们的火柴列表中
And that's it for the x direction.
这就是x方向的情况
And for the y direction, it's the exact same thing.
对于y方向 这是完全相同的
Going down here-- different color, different color, different color,
在这里--不同的颜色
different color, and then same color, same color, different color,
不同的颜色 然后是相同的颜色 相同的颜色 不同的颜色
but number of matches is three because one, two, three, and then
但匹配的数量是三个 因为一 二 三 然后
it's going to walk backwards, up to the top, add that match,
它会向后走 向上走到顶端 添加那个火柴
and then just continue down here.
然后继续往下走
Same thing, same thing, and then same thing there.
一样的东西 一样的东西 然后一样的东西
This is at the end of the column.
这是在本专栏的末尾
So it's going to get to the end.
所以它会一直持续到最后
It's not actually going to look for the next tile
它实际上不会去寻找下一个瓷砖
because there are no more tiles, but every time
因为已经没有瓷砖了 但每次
we complete a row, or a column, we check at the very end,
我们完成一行或一列 我们在最后检查
do we have the number of matches equal to three or greater?
我们有等于或超过三场比赛的比赛次数吗？
If we do, then we need to do the same logic
如果我们这样做了 那么我们需要做同样的逻辑
as we did before by adding that match to our list of matches.
正如我们之前所做的那样 将该匹配添加到我们的匹配列表中
So it's actually quite a simple algorithm, and this is the set of steps
这实际上是一个非常简单的算法 这是一组步骤
that I just illustrated.
我刚才举例说明了这一点
We have a match found there.
我们在那里找到了一根火柴
Oh, sorry. [? Tony, ?] yes?
啊!对不起 [?托尼 ？]是?
AUDIENCE: If you complete two matches at once, would it see both?
观众：如果你同时完成两场比赛 它会同时看到两场比赛吗？
SPEAKER 1: It would.
演讲者1：会的
The question was if you complete two matches at once, would it see both?
问题是 如果你同时完成两场比赛 它会同时看到两场比赛吗？
Yes.
是
If you complete-- and it wouldn't if you deleted
如果你完成了--如果你删除了它就不会了
them as you went because let's say you had like one, two, three here.
因为我们假设你这里有一个 两个 三个
I'm assuming that's what you mean, one, two, three, one, two, three.
我猜你是这个意思 一 二 三 一 二 三
If you just deleted them as you went, then no, it wouldn't see them.
如果你只是随手删除它们 那么不 它不会看到它们
It would go here, it would get these three, delete them,
它会放在这里 它会得到这三个 删除它们
and then it would just see these two.
然后它只会看到这两个人
But because we walk over the entire thing,
但因为我们走过了整件事
and then we only delete matches after all of the matches have processed,
然后 我们只在处理完所有匹配后才删除匹配
we're going to add this one first, and then when we do our vertical one,
我们将首先添加这个 然后当我们做垂直的时候
we're also going to see this one, and so it's going to count as two matches.
我们还会看到这场比赛 所以它将被算作两场比赛
And you could make your code a little bit more complicated if you wanted to,
如果你愿意 你可以让你的代码变得更复杂
and say if there's an intersection between two matches,
假设两个匹配之间有交集
I want to give the player more points.
我想给球员更多的分数
Or I want to give him some sort of effect like in Candy Crush,
或者我想给他一些效果 就像《糖果粉碎传奇》里的那样
I think you get like explosions, or Bejeweled,
我觉得你会像爆炸一样 或者珠光宝气
you get explosions if you get like a T pattern.
如果你得到一个像T形的图案 你就会发生爆炸
And if you get four in a row, you get a laser or something across the screen.
如果你连续四次 屏幕上就会出现激光之类的东西
And actually, part of assignment is clear a row.
实际上 作业的一部分就是清楚地排成一行
If you get four in a row, you should clear that row, or call them.
如果你连续拿到四个 你应该清空那一排 或者打电话给他们
If you do that, then yeah, you can have logic.
如果你这么做了 那么 你就有了逻辑
But currently, all the distro does is just this simple iteration--
但目前 发行版所做的只是一个简单的迭代--
horizontally, then vertically, and adding matches as you go.
先水平 然后垂直 边走边添加火柴
And actually, there is an optimization that you can make.
实际上 有一个优化是可以实现的
If you go here, for example, let's say we're going here, here,
如果你去这里 比如说 我们要去这里 这里
and then we're here, and we're at a different color than the last one.
然后我们来到了这里 我们的颜色与上一次不同
We can just go to the next one.
我们可以直接去下一家
We can just skip because we know we only have two left.
我们可以直接跳过 因为我们知道我们只剩下两个了
There's no point in looking for a match if you're at the n minus 2
如果你是在n减2 那么寻找匹配就没有意义了
because there's no possible way to get a match.
因为找不到匹配的方法
So that's just a shortcut.
所以这只是一条捷径
A little optimization you can make, and that's actually in the code.
您可以进行一些优化 这实际上包含在代码中
Just break off if you're at--
如果你在--就停下来吧
in the code, it's x or y equals 7.
在代码中 x或y等于7
Just break out of that for loop basically,
从根本上说 就是摆脱FOR循环
and go to the next row, or column.
然后转到下一行或下一列
Any more questions as to how that works?
关于它是如何工作的 还有什么问题吗？
If you're actually looking in the code, we won't go over it
如果你真的在看代码 我们不会再看了
in too much detail in class.
在课堂上讲得太详细了
It's fairly straightforward, I think, once I walk you
这很简单 我想 一旦我陪你走
through the algorithm a little bit, but I'll point you to the relevant lines.
通过算法 但我会为您指出相关的行
It's in the play state.
它处于播放状态
No, sorry.
不 对不起
It's in the board in the calculate matches function.
它在黑板上的计算匹配功能中
Here, on line 50, calculate matches.
在这里 第50行 计算匹配项
So horizontal matches, y gets 1 to 8.
所以水平匹配 y得到1到8
You keep a color to match, and basically, you just
你保持颜色相匹配 基本上 你只是
keep track of how many you've matched.
记录一下你匹配了多少个
Match numbers one always when you're doing a brand new color,
当你在做一种全新的颜色时 总是匹配第一个数字
and then starting at x 2 to 8, because we already
然后从x2到8开始 因为我们已经
got the first tile, basically, if the color is the same, increment matchNum.
得到了第一个瓷砖 基本上 如果颜色相同 则递增matchNum
Otherwise, set our current color to that color, the next tile.
否则 将当前颜色设置为下一个磁贴的颜色
If we've done this, and our match is greater than or equal to 3,
如果我们这样做了 并且我们的匹配大于或等于3
then we found a match.
然后我们找到了匹配的
We can add a match.
我们可以添加匹配项
We create a new table.
我们创建一个新表
We go backwards from where we are with x 2 gets x minus 1,
我们从x2的位置倒退得到x减去1
and then x minus matchNum.
然后x减去matchNum
So it works for no matter how long the match is,
所以无论比赛时间有多长 它都是有效的
whether it's three, four, or five.
不管是三个、四个还是五个
And then we're subtracting 1, and then you just
然后我们减去1 然后你就
insert into that match, the tile at that x 2 position
插入到火柴中 该x2位置处瓷砖
because the matches are made of tiles.
因为火柴是用瓷砖做的
So a match is just a group of tiles put together,
所以火柴只是一组瓷砖放在一起
and so you can intersect to any given match just by comparing the tiles,
所以你可以通过比较瓷砖与任何给定的匹配物相交
and just seeing if they have the same tiles, basically.
只是看看它们是否有基本上相同的瓷砖
That's how you'd get a cross match.
这就是你得到交叉匹配的方法
And then after that's all done, just insert into matches that match.
然后在所有操作完成后 只需插入到匹配的火柴中
Here's a little optimization.
这是一个小小的优化
If x is greater than or equal to 7, and this is in part of the loop
如果x大于或等于7 这是循环的一部分
where we already know that we're on a new color from the last color,
我们已经知道我们用的是上一种颜色的新颜色
we'll just break, and then set matchNum to 1 if we haven't gotten to that point
我们将中断 然后将matchNum设置为1(如果我们还没有达到该点
yet.
现在还不行
And then this is the part of the code that accounts for a last row--
然后这是代码的最后一行--
the row ending with a match because we're not going to be on the next loop
行以匹配结束 因为我们不会在下一个循环中
to see whether we're going to a different color.
看看我们是不是要换一种颜色
We just need to check to make sure at the end of any row iteration,
我们只需要检查以确保在任何行迭代结束时
or column iteration when we go to the next row, or column.
或列迭代 当我们转到下一行或列时
Before we go to the next row or column, that matchNum
在我们进入下一行或下一列之前 该matchNum
is greater than or equal to 3, and if so,
大于或等于3 如果是这样
then do the same logic here, but start x at 8.
然后在这里做同样的逻辑 但是从8开始
And same thing for vertical matches.
垂直比赛也是如此
Exact same logic, just x and y are inverted.
完全相同的逻辑 只有x和y是颠倒的
And then that's it.
然后就是这样
And then self.matches, we keep a reference to self.matches in the board
然后是self.matches 我们在黑板上保留对self.matches的引用
so that later we can remove them here, and I
这样以后我们就可以把它们移到这里 而我
believe we use it for something else.
相信我们把它用来做别的事了
And then we return, basically, if the number of matches is greater than 0,
然后我们返回 基本上 如果匹配的数量大于0
we're going to return matches, else we're just going to return false.
我们将返回匹配项 否则将返回False
And we can use this later.
我们以后可以用这个
We can say if matches from our play state,
我们可以说 如果从我们的比赛状态来看
then we can call a few other functions, and bring
然后我们可以调用其他几个函数 并将
in new tiles, and stuff like that.
新瓷砖之类的东西
But just for the sake of being thorough as an illustration,
但为了说明问题的全面性
this is how the algorithm works.
这就是算法的工作原理
In this case, actually, this was before I made the optimization.
在这种情况下 实际上 这是在我进行优化之前
We wouldn't actually do this in this particular case.
在这种情况下 我们实际上不会这样做
This would have shorted down to the next column before it even checked this,
它甚至在检查这个之前就会缩短到下一列
but if your algorithm didn't make that optimization, then yeah,
但如果你的算法没有进行优化 那么是的
I would just see two tiles there.
我只能看到那里有两块瓷砖
Go to the next one, nothing there, no matches.
去下一家 那里什么都没有 没有匹配的
Same thing here.
这里也是一样
There is a match there, and the match would
那里有一场比赛 比赛将会是
be found not at the end of the diagram here,
在这张图的末尾没有发现
it would be calculated when it's pointed here,
当它指向这里时 它会被计算出来
but it knows matchNum is greater than or equal to 3 at that point.
但它知道在该点上matchNum大于或等于3
And it does the exact same thing here.
它在这里做的也是一样的事情
We just go column wise, and then nothing there,
我们只是按列排列 然后什么都没有
nothing there, and then we've got one right there.
那里什么都没有 然后我们就有一个在那里
And so the next part--
所以下一部分--
oh, any questions on how that works at all?
哦 对这是怎么回事有什么问题吗？
The next part-- we have the matches now.
下一部分--我们现在有了火柴
We have them in tables.
我们把它们放在桌子上
We have the tiles.
我们有瓷砖
We have references to the tiles.
我们有关于瓷砖的资料
How do we remove the tiles once we have--
一旦我们有了--我们怎么把瓷砖移走？
how do we get rid of them as soon as we have the matches?
一旦我们有了火柴 我们如何尽快摆脱他们？
Assuming that our board is a table, a 2D table, and each array within there just
假设我们的电路板是一张表 一张2D表 其中的每个数组
has a tile object, how would we clear the board of our tiles?
有一个瓷砖对象 我们如何清除我们的瓷砖板？
AUDIENCE: Are you including what you're shifting [INAUDIBLE]??
观众：你包括你要转移的东西了吗？
SPEAKER 1: No, just remove it from-- just like like.
演讲者1：不 只是把它去掉--就像这样
Just remove it from play.
把它从游戏中移除就行了
AUDIENCE: Oh.
观众：哦
I guess you can [INAUDIBLE]
我想你可以[INAUDIBLE]
SPEAKER 1: Yeah, you could.
演讲者1：是的 你可以
Yeah, with a little bit of finagling, you could get it
是啊 稍微弄虚作假 你就能拿到
to where you could set a tile to be invisible,
你可以将瓷砖设置为隐形
and then you could just give it a new tile ID, I guess,
然后你可以给它一个新的磁贴ID 我想
and then shift it up above, and then make it come.
然后把它移到上面 然后让它来
Well, I don't know if that approach necessarily
我不知道这种方法是否有必要
works super well for this because of gravity
由于地心引力的缘故 这方面的效果非常好
because the tiles have to come down.
因为瓷砖必须要拆下来
So then you'd have to bring the lower ones, if they were at the bottom here.
因此 如果它们在这里的底部 那么你必须带上较低的那些
Those would have to come down.
这些将不得不降下来
That kind of approach would be a little tricky.
这种方法可能会有点棘手
You could make it work, I think.
我想 你可以让它发挥作用
The simple approach, which we used in this distro,
我们在这个发行版中使用的简单方法
is actually just setting them to nil because if you set something to nil,
实际上就是将它们设置为零 因为如果您将某个值设置为零
it's just not going to render, in this case.
在这种情况下 它只是不会呈现
So we're just setting all of these tiles that were previously there to nil.
因此 我们只是将所有以前在那里的瓷砖设置为零
They're nothing at this point.
在这一点上 他们什么都不是
They effectively would render like this if you tried to render them,
如果您尝试渲染它们 它们实际上会像这样渲染
assuming that your code accounted for it, or it didn't break.
假设您的代码说明了这一点 或者它没有崩溃
And then the next stage would be the actual getting the board fixed
然后下一步就是实际修好电路板
because we have the tiles removed.
因为我们已经把瓷砖移走了
So now, we have this thing here, but there
所以现在 我们这里有这个东西 但在那里
is a step that has to happen before we get new tiles, and that's gravity.
这是在我们得到新瓷砖之前必须完成的一个步骤 这就是重力
We have to actually shift everything down.
我们真的要把所有东西都往下移
So how do we go about shifting tiles down?
那么 我们如何着手将瓷砖向下移动呢？
So this first column, we don't really have to do anything, right?
所以在第一篇专栏中 我们不需要做任何事情 对吗？
This column is all set, but what about this column?
这一栏都准备好了 但这一栏呢？
How would we shift?
我们将如何转移？
How would we get that tile to go down?
我们怎么才能把瓷砖铺下去呢？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不见]
SPEAKER 1: Sorry?
演讲者1：什么？
AUDIENCE: Tweens again?
观众：又是青少年？
SPEAKER 1: Tweens.
演讲者1：青少年
Yes, we could do it with tweens, but from a data structure
是的 我们可以使用Tweens 但从数据结构
standpoint, how would we--
立场 我们怎么.
because that will just tween the xy, but that won't necessarily
因为这只会在XY之间 但不一定
fix-- the underlying data structure still
修复--底层数据结构仍然
has to represent-- because we're going to do iterations over it,
必须代表--因为我们将对其进行迭代
we have to have references to the tiles in the right spots.
我们必须在正确的位置引用瓷砖
AUDIENCE: So just shifting it was the table
观众：所以就是把桌子移开
from the fourth row to the fifth row.
从第四排到第五排
SPEAKER 1: So how would you start by getting this tile down
演讲者1：那么你怎么开始取下这块瓷砖
to this position?
到了这个位置？
AUDIENCE: Switching it from the fourth row to the fifth row.
观众：把它从第四排换到第五排
SPEAKER 1: You would.
演讲者1：你会的
How would your algorithm work step by step to making sure that would happen?
你的算法将如何一步一步地工作 以确保实现这一点？
AUDIENCE: Is it start from the bottom, and if that's nil, it would go up more
观众：它是从底部开始的吗 如果是零 它会上升更多
SPEAKER 1: Exactly.
演讲者1：完全正确
That's exactly you do.
这就是你要做的
You start from the bottom, and then whenever we have anything that's nil,
你从底层开始 然后当我们有任何东西是零的时候
we need to look for the first tile above it that's not nil, and shift it down.
我们需要寻找它上面的第一个不是零的瓷砖 然后将它向下移动
So in this case, we start from the bottom, and we go up this way.
所以在这种情况下 我们从底部开始 我们沿着这条路向上
Not nil, not nil, not nil, not nil, not nil.
不是零 不是零
So none of those are spaces in the code.
所以这些都不是代码中的空格
It's called spaceY, or space and spaceY.
这叫Spacey 或称Space and Spacey
So we go to the next column over, and we only
所以我们转到下一个专栏 我们只
have to check vertically in this case.
在这种情况下 必须垂直检查
We don't have to do a horizontal check for anything
我们不需要对任何东西进行横向检查
because gravity can only follow in one direction.
因为重力只能沿着一个方向
So we just go over here.
所以我们就从这里走过去
So we're only looping through this code, effectively, in this case, five times,
所以我们只循环了这段代码 在这种情况下 有效地 五次
but in our code, eight times.
但在我们的代码中 是八次
But it needs to be a while loop rather than a for loop,
但它需要是WHILE循环而不是FOR循环
and we'll see why in a second.
我们一会儿就会知道原因
But start here.
但从这里开始吧
We see oh, we have a space there.
我们看到了 哦 我们在那里有一个空间
So what we need to do is say, OK, the lowest space is here.
所以我们需要做的是 好的 最低的空间在这里
So we need to look for the next tile above it, and shift it down.
所以我们需要寻找它上面的下一个瓷砖 然后将它向下移动
So we keep a reference to this, and we look up here,
所以我们把这个作为参考 我们在这里寻找
and we say oh, this is a tile.
我们会说 哦 这是一块瓷砖
Perfect.
完美无缺
So I'm just going to take this tile, and I'm
所以我要拿着这块瓷砖 我
going to set that space index to that tile,
将空间索引设置为该磁贴
and then I'm going to set this index to nil.
然后我会把这个指数设置为零
And then we just have to start again, though, from here
然后我们只需要重新开始 从这里开始
because this tile is now space.
因为这块瓷砖现在是太空了
So we have to look up here, and say OK, so basically, our y counter
所以我们必须抬头看这里 然后说好的 所以基本上 我们的y计数器
stays at that thing, and then just goes back up because our y counter could,
保持在那个位置 然后返回 因为我们的y计数器可以
theoretically, come all the way up here before it finds a tile,
从理论上讲 在它找到瓷砖之前大老远跑到这里来
and then shift it all the way down, but we can't just-- or here, let's
然后把它一直往下移 但我们不能--或者在这里 让我们
say there are two tiles right here.
假设这里有两块瓷砖
Our y counter might end up here because these are all spaces,
我们的y计数器可能会在这里结束 因为这些都是空格
and the tile gets shifted down here, but we can't just
瓷砖被移到这里 但我们不能
start our y counter back here again, and go up to the next tile,
在这里重新开始我们的y计数器 然后转到下一个瓷砖
and look for spaces because we have all these spaces down here.
并寻找空间 因为我们这里有所有的空间
So it's a while loop.
所以这是一个While循环
So while, basically, there are no spaces on any of these points,
所以 虽然这些点基本上都没有空格
we need to make sure that we keep lowering the tile.
我们需要确保我们继续降低瓦片
So keep a reference here, tile here, bring it down, space here.
所以在这里保留一个参考 在这里瓷砖 把它放下来 在这里留出空间
So we keep a reference with space.
所以我们保留了一个空间的参照
We say oh, there's a space here now.
我们说 哦 这里现在有一个空间
We can look all the way up, but there's no tiles anywhere.
我们可以往上看 但到处都没有瓷砖
So we know that we can just move onto the next iteration of the loop.
所以我们知道我们可以继续循环的下一次迭代
We haven't found any tiles.
我们没有找到任何瓷砖
We don't need to bother with it.
我们不需要为它操心
Same thing here.
这里也是一样
We have a space reference here, tile, found a tile,
我们有一个太空参考 瓷砖 找到了一块瓷砖
shift it down, space here, tile here,
向下移动 这里的空间 这里的瓷砖 向下移动 这里的空间 这里的瓷砖
shift it down, space, space, done, and then we rinse, and repeat that.
向下移动 空格 空格 完成 然后我们冲洗 重复这个过程
It's kind of almost like a bubble sort type of algorithm.
这几乎是一种泡泡排序型算法
Not a sort, but it has the same sort of look and behavior to it, more or less.
不是一种 但它或多或少有相同的外观和行为
Here's just a visual illustration of it.
这只是它的一个视觉插图
So start from the bottom, go up, we're looking for spaces here.
所以从底部开始 向上 我们在这里寻找空间
No spaces; column is perfectly stable.
没有空格；柱子非常稳定
We found a space here, tile is there, shift it down.
我们在这里找到了一个空间 瓷砖在那里 把它往下移
Restart the loop from the tile, space, space, space, no more spaces;
重新启动循环从瓷砖 空格 没有更多的空格；
column stable.
柱子稳定
Space found, tile found, shift, space found, tile found, shift, space found,
找到的空间、找到的磁贴、移位、找到的空间、找到的磁贴、移位、找到的空间
tile found, shift, and so on, and so forth.
平铺已找到、移位等
And so that's the gist.
这就是要点所在
Super, super basic.
超级 超级基础
But now we actually have to replace the tiles.
但现在我们实际上必须更换瓷砖
AUDIENCE: You don't even need to check.
观众：你甚至不需要检查
Once you shift a block down, you don't even
一旦你向下移动一个街区 你甚至不会
need to check the space above it, whether it's a space
需要检查其上方的空间 是否为空间
or not because you know that's automatically a space when you just
或者不是因为你知道当你只是
shifted a block, right?
移了一个街区 对吧？
SPEAKER 1: Yeah.
演讲者1：是的
Actually, that's true.
事实上 这是真的
Yeah, I guess in that case, you wouldn't need to.
是啊 我想如果是那样的话 你就不需要了
But we do need a reference to that space, and keep checking above it.
但我们确实需要一个关于那个空间的参考 并继续检查它上面的
But yeah, I guess you probably don't need, necessarily,
但是 是的 我想你可能不一定需要
to check whether it's a space or not.
检查它是否是空格
You can just assume it's a space, and I actually think my code does that.
您可以假设它是一个空格 而我实际上认为我的代码可以做到这一点
I'm not 100% sure off the top of my head.
我不是百分之百确定我的头顶
We can check, and see.
我们可以查一查 看看
I think it's down here.
我想它就在下面
No?
不是吗？
Is it?
是吗?
Oh no, it's in get falling tiles, I think, which is on line 177.
哦 不 我想是在落地砖店 是177线
So for 1 to 8 in x, we keep a spaceY.
因此 对于1到8英寸x 我们保留一个空格
So spaceY, we set it zero because that's just a variable.
所以Spacey 我们把它设为零 因为这只是一个变量
We don't have a space yet.
我们还没有空位
So just because you can't index a tile--
所以 不能为瓷砖编制索引--
you can index Lua tables by zero, but because they're not by default,
您可以通过零来索引Lua表 但是因为它们不是缺省的
we're just setting the zero as like our false space flag.
我们只是把零设置成像我们的假太空旗帜一样
y gets 8, starting at the bottom.
Y得到8 从底部开始
So while y is greater than or equal to 1, tile gets self.tiles y of x.
所以当y大于或等于1时 瓦片得到x的自瓦片y
In that case, it's going to be at the eighth position.
那样的话 它将排在第八位
So space is set to false, but space is our space
因此 space设置为False 但space是我们的空间
found flag, and also whether or not the tile that we just looked at
找到旗帜 以及我们刚才看到的瓷砖是否
was a space.
是一个空间
Sorry, no, it's just our space flag.
抱歉 不 这只是我们的太空旗帜
We check to see if there is a tile at our current position.
我们检查一下 看看我们现在的位置是否有瓷砖
So recall, everything gets set to nil.
所以请记住 一切都被设置为零
So we can just say local tile gets self.tiles y x.
所以我们可以说局部瓦片是自的 瓦片y x
This will be nil if there was no tile there.
如果那里没有瓷砖 这将是零
So if tile, which means if it's not nil, if it equal something, spaceY of x
所以如果平铺 这意味着如果它不是零 如果它等于某个东西 x的空格
is going to equal that tile.
将与那块瓷砖持平
We keep a reference to spaceY, which is our last space.
我们保留了对Spacey的引用 这是我们最后的空间
We set tile.gridY to spaceY because we have to reset it to gridY.
我们将tile.gridY设置为Spacey 因为我们必须将其重置为Gridy
We're going to tween it here.
我们将在这里讨论这个问题
This is how we actually get the falling, tweening behavior.
这就是我们实际上如何得到跌倒、补丁的行为
We're going to tween it's y to tile.gridY minus 1 times 32,
我们将在y到tile.GridY减去1乘以32之间
recall, because coordinates are zero based, but Lua tables are one indexed.
回想一下 因为坐标是从零开始的 但是Lua表是1索引的
Space is false, y is spaceY, and then spaceY gets zero.
空格是假的 y是Spacey 然后Spacey得零
Basically, we're going to start at the--
基本上 我们将从--开始
we're going to put spaceY to that tile, and then we're
我们要把Spacey放在瓷砖上 然后我们
going to set spaceY to 0.
将Spacey设置为0
I think it actually does, in this case, it is actually checking that tile
我认为它实际上是这样做的 在这种情况下 它实际上是在检查瓷砖
to make sure that it's--
以确保它是--
yeah, because it's just getting set to the tile--
是的 因为它刚刚被设置到瓷砖上--
spaceY being the tile that we just replaced, and just put
Spacey是我们刚刚更换的瓷砖 只是放在
into an actual spot.
变成了一个真实的地点
So it does actually make the check up above to see whether that's a space
所以它确实在上面做了检查 看看这是不是一个空格
or not.
或者不去
Only one caveat though actually is--
但实际上只有一个需要注意的地方--
actually, no, that wouldn't be true.
实际上 不 那不是真的
I was going to say, if you're at the top of the screen,
我想说的是 如果你在屏幕的顶端
but no because there's no way we can be at the top of the screen,
但不是因为我们不可能站在屏幕的顶端
and have-- yeah, I don't think it would work.
而且--是的 我觉得这行不通
A small optimization you could make is you just assume always a space.
您可以做的一个小优化就是假设总是有一个空格
Yeah.
嗯
That's the get falling tiles in a nut shell,
这就是坚果壳里掉落的瓷砖
or at least the ones that are falling from gravity.
或者至少是那些从重力中坠落的物体
And then we also have tiles that we want to add to replace them,
然后我们也有我们想要添加的瓷砖来取代它们
and so we'll see that here.
我们会在这里看到这一点
So this code.
所以这个代码
So what we need to do to replace--
所以我们需要做的是取代--
what do you guys think we need to do to get replacement tiles?
你们认为我们需要做些什么来更换瓷砖？
AUDIENCE: Check response, and check if it's empty, [INAUDIBLE]
观众：检查回应 检查是否为空 [INAUDIBLE]
but if it's not, then you're done.
但如果不是 那你就完了
SPEAKER 1: Yeah, exactly.
演讲者1：是的 没错
So the response was check to see from the top
因此 从顶层查看了响应
if there are any tiles that are empty, and if there are,
如果有空的瓷砖 如果有
then spawn some tiles, and then ideally, tween them to their new positions.
然后产生一些瓷砖 然后理想情况下 将它们补间到它们的新位置
You can basically just assign them to their values here.
您基本上可以在这里将它们赋给它们的值
So what we need to do, actually, though, is
所以我们需要做的是 实际上
if we spawn a tile up here to put into any of these positions, their gridY's
如果我们在这里生产一块瓷砖放在这些位置中的任何一个 他们的Gridy
need to be set in advance because they're
需要提前设置 因为它们是
going to occupy that space anyway.
无论如何都要占据那个空间
Their actual y position needs to be tweened.
他们的实际y位置需要调整
So because the x and the y are separate from the gridY, and the gridX,
所以因为x和y与Gridy和GridX是分开的
those are just table indices, but not their coordinates.
这些只是表索引 而不是它们的坐标
We can tween those, and it won't actually
我们可以在它们之间加补丁 但实际上不会
have any effect on the data structure.
对数据结构有任何影响
The data structure itself can maintain-- we can still use the data structure--
数据结构本身可以维护--我们仍然可以使用数据结构--
put a tile in its right spot in our table,
把一块瓷砖放在我们桌子上的正确位置
and then give it the right gridX, and gridY, but tween the x and y value.
然后给它正确的GridX和Gridy 但要介于x和y之间
We can do whatever we want with those.
我们可以用这些钱做任何我们想做的事
We can make them spin around, and stuff as long
我们可以让他们旋转 和东西一样长
as the data structure is intact, and ideally,
因为数据结构是完好无损的 理想情况下
as long as we can't input while it's doing it's movement,
只要我们不能在它移动的时候输入
and stuff like that because that could create some visual bugs.
诸如此类的东西 因为这可能会产生一些视觉上的错误
And so what we do is we actually disable input when a swap is taking place,
因此 我们所做的实际上是在交换发生时禁用输入
and you'll see that in the distribution code.
您将在分发代码中看到这一点
But yes, count how many spaces there are.
但是的 数一数有多少空位
Spawn four tiles, spawn two tiles, spawn two tiles
产生四个瓦片 产生两个瓦片 产生两个瓦片
spawn four tiles that have already been given their right gridX, gridY,
产生四个已经被赋予了正确的GRIDX的瓷砖 格里迪
and then just tween their y to wherever it needs to go.
然后就在他们的y到它需要去的地方之间
It's gridY times 32--
这是格里迪的32倍
gridY minus 1 times 32.
格里迪减去1乘32
And so that's what we're doing here.
这就是我们在这里做的事情
We're just count, and then boop.
我们只是在数 然后砰的一声
That was my favorite part of putting this show together.
这是我把这部剧组合在一起最喜欢的部分
And so we're going to get into a couple of minutes of talking about sprites,
因此 我们将用几分钟的时间来谈论精灵
and palettes, but I think the one thing--
和调色板 但我认为有一件事--
blanking for a second.
一秒钟的空白
I was going to talk about one last thing.
我还想说最后一件事
Let me see if I can figure out what that was.
让我看看我能不能搞清楚那是什么
Oh, right, so in the board--
哦 对了 所以在黑板上--
sorry, in the play state, I believe, is where this is, there is a function.
对不起 在播放状态下 我相信这就是它的位置 有一个功能
So play state has it's own calculateMatches, basically,
所以Play State基本上有它自己的计算匹配
where it waits for you to--
它在那里等着你--
where once you've basically swapped any two tiles,
一旦你基本上交换了任何两块瓷砖
it will calculate whether those tiles have made a match.
它将计算这些瓷砖是否匹配
And we're going to get matches via self.board calculateMatches,
我们将通过自己的黑板计算匹配来获得匹配
the function that we were looking at before.
我们之前看到的函数
If there are any matches--
如果有匹配的--
well, we play a sound effect here for every match.
嗯 我们这里每场比赛都有音效
This is where you also calculate the score.
这也是计算分数的地方
You just multiply the number of tiles in a match by 50,
你只需将一场比赛中的瓷砖数量乘以50
and part of the assignment will be adding some value
任务的一部分将是增加一些价值
to the individual varieties of the tiles.
不同种类的瓷砖
Here, we tween.
在这里 我们在一起
So we return also from the board class a table
所以我们也从董事会班回来了一张桌子
of tweens for all of the new tiles that we just spawned,
对于我们刚刚催生的所有新瓷砖
and so what we're going to end up doing is tweening all of them here.
所以我们最终要做的就是把它们都补齐
So notice that we're passing in a timer.tween,
所以请注意 我们传入了一个计时器 tweet
this variable, tilesToFall.
该变量为tilesToFall
That's a definition file that we're just returning from our board class.
这是一个定义文件 我们刚刚从我们的董事会班上返回
And so once those are all finished, then we get new tiles,
一旦所有这些都完成了 我们就会得到新的瓷砖
and then we tween here.
然后我们在这里相聚
I think this line is redundant, actually.
事实上 我认为这条线路是多余的
I think this might have been a debugging line.
我认为这可能是一条调试线
I don't think we need this.
我不认为我们需要这个
No, we don't need this at all.
不 我们根本不需要这个
So sorry.
真的很抱歉
This is the important part.
这是最重要的部分
We're going to tween--
我们要去青春节--
wait, we do need it.
等等 我们确实需要它
Self.board getNewTiles.
Self.board获取NewTiles
What am I thinking of?
我在想什么呢？
Sorry, a little bit confused for a second.
抱歉 我有点困惑
I thought this was an empty function that I defined.
我以为这是我定义的一个空函数
Get new tiles.
买新的瓷砖
Yeah, this returns an empty table.
是的 这会返回一个空桌子
But basically, the gist of it is the play
但从根本上说 它的主旨是剧本
state, when it calls this function, it will call itself every time.
状态 当它调用此函数时 它每次都会调用自身
And I think this is actually having the result of doing it
我认为这实际上是在产生这样做的结果
instantly here because newTiles is just an empty table.
马上就到了 因为新Tiles只是一张空桌子
I think all this should be is just this inside all of this like that.
我认为这一切都应该是这样的 这一切都是这样的
But that has the result of calling itself again
但这样做的结果是 它再次自称
because when we get new tiles coming from the top of the screen,
因为当我们从屏幕顶部获得新的磁贴时
we could potentially have a case where we've gotten some matches,
我们可能会有一个案子 我们找到一些匹配的
and it's not shown here, but new falling tiles could give us new matches.
这里没有显示 但新落下的瓷砖可能会给我们带来新的火柴
So after we calculate matches, let's say maybe this tile dropped here,
所以在我们计算了匹配后 假设这块瓷砖掉在了这里
but it was a purple, and these two were already there.
但它是紫色的 而这两个人已经在那里了
We've already calculated matches, but then we
我们已经计算了匹配 但后来我们
need to do it again, and then do it again if it keeps happening.
需要再做一次 如果它继续发生 就再做一次
And so you should be recursively call self calculateMatches
因此您应该递归地调用Self CalculateMatches
in that case, which will have the effect of accomplishing that because this
在这种情况下 这将具有实现这一点的效果 因为这
will always look for matches.
会一直寻找匹配的对象
And so when we call self calculateMatches here, over, and over
因此 当我们在这里调用Self CalculateMatches时 一遍又一遍
again, until there are no matches--
再说一次 直到没有匹配--
as long as there are matches, this should keep happening.
只要有比赛 这种情况就应该继续发生
You should keep getting scores, and tiles should keep getting cleared.
你应该不断地得分 瓷砖应该不断地被清除
But as soon as that's not the case anymore,
但一旦情况不再是这样
then self.canInput equals true, and we're not calculating matches anymore.
则self.canInput等于真 我们不再计算匹配项
We don't recursively call the function anymore, and we're done.
我们不再递归地调用该函数 我们就完成了
And so that's just the point I wanted to illustrate.
这就是我想要说明的观点
Got slightly confused by, I think, what was a vestige of my old code.
我想 我对我的旧代码的遗迹感到有点困惑
Maybe I was trying something, but I think this, ultimately,
也许我是在尝试什么 但我认为 最终
should just be this, and I'll test it, and make sure, and then push
应该是这样的 我会测试它 并确保 然后按
the change.
这一变化
And it doesn't need to be over 0.25 seconds.
它不需要超过0.25秒
It can just be instant.
它可以是瞬间的
Palettes, really quickly, with something I wanted to cover,
调色板 非常快 有一些我想要涵盖的东西
which was just the idea of taking art, and then just-- and I
这只是一个想法 把艺术 然后--和我
have a couple of cool examples to show.
有几个很酷的例子可以展示
Just taking some sort of picture, and then giving it--
只是拍了一些照片 然后给它--
only using or some sort of image, and only using 32, in this case,
仅使用或某种类型的图像 并且仅使用32 在本例中
or some arbitrary number of colors.
或者一些任意数量的颜色
This is some fancy stuff that some person named DawnBringer online did.
这是一个叫DawnBringer Online的人做的一些奇特的东西
He generated a very famous 32 color palette called DawnBringer's 32 color
他生成了一个非常著名的32色调色板 名为DawnBringer的32色
palette.
调色板
But basically, it allows--
但基本上 它允许--
this is done with just 32 colors we see on the screen.
这是用我们在屏幕上看到的32种颜色完成的
Those are all dithered.
这些都是摇摆不定的
Dithering is a term which means to just draw two colors pixel by pixel,
抖动是一个术语 意思是逐个像素地绘制两种颜色
interleaved, so that from far away it looks like a brand new color,
交错 所以从远处看它就像是一种全新的颜色
and this is a dithering chart.
这是一张抖动图
This just shows you every color here at the very top.
这只是向你展示了最上面的每种颜色
These are all 32 colors.
这些都是32种颜色
These are 32, and those are 32 intersected with each other such
这些是32个 而那些是彼此相交的32个
that they're just like dot, dot, dot, dot, dot.
他们就像圆点 圆点
Every other dot is every other color.
每一个点都是另一个颜色
And so you can do some pretty amazing things with just a few colors.
所以你可以用几种颜色做一些令人惊叹的事情
This is actually done with 16 colors.
这实际上是用16种颜色来完成的
All four of those are only 16 colors.
这四种颜色都只有16种
This is just to show you what it looks like when you do it to an actual image.
这只是为了向您展示当您对实际图像执行此操作时它看起来是什么样子
This is an example of what using a color palette on an image that
这是一个在图像上使用调色板的示例
doesn't work well with it looks like.
看起来效果不是很好
So this is a regular image with I don't know
所以这是一张规则的图像 我不知道
how many colors, thousands of millions of colors, and this
有多少种颜色 几百万种颜色 还有这个
is using DawnBringer's 32 color palette.
正在使用DawnBringer的32色调色板
So still looks very similar to what it should.
因此 它看起来仍然与应有的非常相似
It's a cat, but there's a lot of weird things going on in the background
这是一只猫 但背景里有很多奇怪的事情
because taking an image with a lot of blur, and a lot of distorted color,
因为拍摄一张有很多模糊和大量扭曲色彩的图像
has the effect of giving you blotchy patterns when you go down
有这样的效果 当你倒下的时候 你会看到斑点图案
to a few colors.
几种颜色
But this is an example of an image that has a lot of flatter colors.
但这是一个图像的例子 它有很多更平坦的颜色
There's still a lot of colors in this image.
这张图片中仍然有很多颜色
There are some shades, and stuff like that, but this is thousands of colors,
有一些色调 诸如此类的东西 但这是成千上万种颜色
and this is 32 colors.
这是32种颜色
So clearly, if you do it on the right thing,
所以很明显 如果你做了正确的事情
you can actually get really good effects with it.
实际上 你可以用它获得非常好的效果
And so again, not a whole lot of difference, but this one's
所以再一次 没有太大的区别 但这一次
got I don't know how many hundreds of thousands of colors,
我不知道有多少几十万种颜色
and this one's only got 32.
而这一张只有32张
And so how it ties back into what we're doing
所以它是如何与我们正在做的事情联系起来的
is this is using a 32-bit color or 32 color palette on purpose.
这是故意使用32位颜色还是32色调色板
This is actually DawnBringer's 32 color palette.
这实际上是DawnBringer的32色调色板
Breakout used the same palette, 32 colors,
Breakout使用相同的调色板 32种颜色
and a lot of our 2D future lectures will use limited color palettes.
我们未来的许多2D课程将使用有限的调色板
If you're trying to draw sprite art, and you want some quick, and easy ways just
如果你正在尝试画精灵艺术 并且你想要一些快速 简单的方法
to give your work a little bit of consistency,
为了给你的工作带来一点一致性
I recommend trying to pick 8, or 16, or 32 colors,
我建议试着挑选8、16或32种颜色
and just adhering to using just those.
而只是坚持只使用这些
And you'd be surprised at how much you get out
你会惊讶于你从中得到了多少
of it, and how much more cohesive your work will look just
以及你的工作看起来会有多有凝聚力
by imposing that constraint on you.
通过把这个限制强加给你
It's an artifact of a real world constraint of former hardware.
它是前硬件现实世界约束下的产物
The NES only had so many colors it could color each sprite,
NES只有那么多颜色可以给每个精灵上色
like four colors, or something that.
比如四种颜色 或者类似的东西
And so you also get a-- if you're going for an authentic retro look,
所以你也会得到一个--如果你想要一个真正的复古造型
it will help you in that sense.
从这个意义上说 它会对你有所帮助
And then different from palettes, but related
然后不同于调色板 但相关
is palette swapping, which is another term you've probably heard,
调色板互换 这是你可能听说过的另一个术语
which is basically all of these Mario sprites--
基本上就是所有这些马里奥精灵--
they'll probably start with a gray scale Mario, some like gray version
他们可能会从灰度级的马里奥开始 有些像灰色版本
where each of these separate colors are mapped out
其中每一种不同的颜色都被绘制出来
to some table where one equals red, two equals blue, or whatever.
一张等于红色 两张等于蓝色 或者其他什么的桌子
And then you can just shift all of them, and then you
然后你可以把它们全部移开 然后你
get all of these different nice effects, assuming
得到所有这些不同的美好效果 假设
that you've created a good palette.
你创造了一个很好的调色板
You can get a lot of reuse, and this is actually
你可以得到大量的重复使用 这实际上是
how Super Mario Bros. used to do some of its programming.
超级马里奥兄弟过去是如何制作一些节目的
The clouds and the bushes were the same sprite.
云朵和灌木丛是同一个精灵
One was just colored green.
其中一个只是涂成了绿色
It was palette swapped green from the white that the cloud was colored.
它的调色板从白色变成了绿色 那就是云是彩色的
So that's the gist of Match 3.
这就是第三场比赛的要点
Assignment 3 is going to have a few parts to it.
作业3会有几个部分
So time addition on matches.
所以在比赛中增加时间
So when you get a match, you should get time added to the clock.
因此 当你得到一个匹配 你应该得到时间增加到时钟
Currently, right now, you only get 60 seconds.
目前 你只有60秒的时间
It's a little bit hard to actually get past level two at this point.
在这一点上 要真正通过第二级是有点困难的
So getting points for every tile in a match.
所以比赛中的每一块瓷砖都能得到积分
Make it so that level one starts with simple flat blocks.
让它成为第一级从简单的扁平积木开始
So earlier, we saw the array of tiles, and it
早些时候 我们看到了瓷砖阵列 它
was flat tiles on the first index of every color row,
在每个颜色行的第一个索引上都是扁平的瓷砖
but there were several other patterns like x's, and circles, and triangles,
但还有其他几种图案 比如x 圆圈和三角形
and stuff.
诸如此类的
Make those worth some higher amount of value, each one.
让那些价值更高的东西 每一件都有价值
Create random shiny variants of blocks that will destroy an entire row when
创建随机的闪闪发光的块变体 在以下情况下将销毁整行
you get a match.
你会得到一个匹配的
So have a block.
所以 来个街区吧
It should have some field, shiny or something.
它应该有一些领域 闪闪发光或什么的
If it's shiny, render it with something to make it look shiny.
如果它很有光泽 就用一些东西来渲染它 让它看起来很有光泽
You can use particle effect if you want.
如果需要 可以使用粒子效果
You can put a very opaque, or a very transparent maybe yellowish or whitish
你可以把一个很不透明的 或者一个很透明的 可能发黄或发白
rectangle on it to give it a brighter look.
长方形在上面 让它看起来更明亮
And then if it's in a match, that entire row
如果它在匹配中 那么整排
should get cleared instead of just that match.
应该清白而不只是那场比赛
Only allow swapping when it results in a match.
仅当结果匹配时才允许交换
This is an important thing because right now, mathematically,
这是一件重要的事情 因为现在 从数学上讲
it's actually very unlikely that you'll get a board that
实际上 你不太可能得到一块
has matches on it to begin with.
一开始就有火柴
So you're going to have to pick a subset of tiles in your implementation,
因此 您将不得不在您的实现中选择瓷砖的子集
and actually use those instead of just using all of them.
并实际使用它们 而不是全部使用它们
Pick six tiles, which you can get variants on, or just whatever flat
挑选六块瓷砖 你可以在上面贴上各种不同的瓷砖 或者随便什么
colors, and then use only those to spawn your board.
颜色 然后只使用这些来产卵您的板
Don't use all 18, or however many there are.
不要用掉所有的18个 或者不管有多少个
And then optional, if you're curious, if you want, probably,
然后是可选的 如果你好奇 如果你想 很可能
an arguably better gaming experience with this,
这款游戏可以说是更好的游戏体验
just implement actually playing with the mouse.
只要实现真正玩鼠标就行了
Being able to click and drag, or just click individual tiles.
能够点击并拖动 或者只需点击单个磁贴
And to do that, you will need to convert--
要做到这一点 你需要转换--
because we use the push library for virtual resolution,
因为我们使用推送库进行虚拟解析
you'll need to convert the window mouse coordinates
您需要转换窗口鼠标坐标
to push coordinates so that they'll map into the game space appropriately,
来推动坐标 这样它们就会适当地映射到游戏空间中
and so you'll use a function called push to game, where
因此 您将使用一个名为Push to Game的函数 其中
it takes an x and y, where the x and the y will be your mouse coordinates.
它需要x和y 其中x和y将是您的鼠标坐标
Next time, we're actually going to get into a little bit
下一次 我们实际上会进入一个
more robust of a game, arguably, like a Mario clone.
更健壮的游戏 可以说 就像马里奥的克隆体
This is actually where this course started
本课程实际上就是从这里开始的
was I taught a seminar on Super Mario Bros.
我是不是教过一个关于超级马里奥兄弟的研讨会
We won't be using Super Mario Bros. assets because of copyright,
我们不会因为版权的原因而使用超级马里奥兄弟的资产
but we'll be using this tile sheet here, which is very similar.
但我们将在这里使用这块瓷砖 它非常相似
It's got a nice aesthetic.
它有一种很好的美感
We'll cover tile maps.
我们将介绍瓷砖地图
So how to generate levels using individual tiles.
那么如何使用单独的瓷砖来生成关卡
2D animation, so rather than just like static things
2D动画 所以不只是喜欢静态的东西
that we've had going on so far, you'll have characters that actually walk,
到目前为止我们一直在做的是 你会有真正会走路的角色
and jump, and do different things.
跳起来 做不同的事情
We'll talk about how to actually procedure
我们将讨论如何实际操作
generate platformer levels, which isn't terribly difficult.
生成平台级别 这并不是特别困难
It sounds kind of difficult, but it's actually pretty--
这听起来有点难 但实际上很漂亮--
for very simple stuff, it's not too bad.
对于非常简单的事情来说 这并不是太糟糕
Basic platformer physics, so hitting blocks, and jumping,
基本的平台物理学 所以击球 跳跃
and stuff like that.
诸如此类的事情
We've covered a lot of that with Flappy Bird, actually, and actually,
事实上 我们已经在Flappy Bird中讲述了很多这一点 实际上
the bricks from Breakout kind of tie into it a little bit.
《越狱》中的砖块有点搭在一起
Hurt boxes so we can have enemies that hurt you, and visa versa.
伤害盒子 这样我们就可以有伤害你的敌人 反之亦然
And power ups so that you can change your state in some way to make you
并通电 这样你就可以以某种方式改变你的状态 让你
larger, or invincible, or whatnot.
更大 或所向披靡 或诸如此类
That was Match 3.
那是第三场比赛
Thanks a lot, and see you next time.
非常感谢 下次再见